[
    {
        "front": "elev (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "student",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "lärare (-n, –, -lärarna)",
        "back": "teacher",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Ursäkta.",
        "back": "Excuse me.",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Kan du säga det en gång till?",
        "back": "Could you repeat that?",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Jag har en fråga.",
        "back": "I have a question.",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Vad betyder det?",
        "back": "What does that mean?",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Hur säger man ... på svenska?",
        "back": "How do you say ... in Swedish?",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Vad heter ... på svenska?",
        "back": "What is ... called in Swedish?",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Hur uttalar man ... ?",
        "back": "How do you pronounce ... ?",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Jag förstår inte.",
        "back": "I don't understand.",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Hur stavar/skriver man ... ?",
        "back": "How do you spell/write ... ?",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Jaha! Nu förstår jag!",
        "back": "Ah! Now I understand!",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Förstår du/ni?",
        "back": "Do you understand?",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Har ni några frågor?",
        "back": "Do you have any questions?",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Titta på sidan X i textboken/övningsboken.",
        "back": "Look at page X in the textbook/exercise book.",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Läs texten på sidan X.",
        "back": "Read the text on page X.",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Stäng boken.",
        "back": "Close the book.",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Lyssna.",
        "back": "Listen.",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Säg efter mig.",
        "back": "Repeat after me.",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Skriv!",
        "back": "Write!",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Arbeta i par.",
        "back": "Work in pairs.",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Prata svenska!",
        "back": "Speak Swedish.",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "kombinera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "combine",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "foto (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "photo",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "och",
        "back": "and",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "ord (-et, –, -en)",
        "back": "word",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "lampa (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "lamp",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "bok (-en, böcker, böckerna)",
        "back": "book",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "dator (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "computer",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "buss (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "bus",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "te (-et, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "tea",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "mobil (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "cell phone / mobile phone",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "penna (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "pen",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "kaffe (-et)",
        "back": "coffee",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "lång (-t, -a)",
        "back": "long",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "vokal (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "vowel",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "eller",
        "back": "or",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "konsonant (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "consonant",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "exempel (exemplet, –, exemplen)",
        "back": "example",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "namn (-et, –, -en)",
        "back": "name",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "språk (-et, –, -en)",
        "back": "language",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "land (-et, länder, länderna)",
        "back": "country",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Vad heter du?",
        "back": "What is your name?",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Jag heter",
        "back": "My name is",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "jag",
        "back": "I",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "heta (heter, hette, hetat)",
        "back": "be called",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "varifrån",
        "back": "from where",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "komma (kommer, kom, kommit)",
        "back": "come",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "från",
        "back": "from",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Grekland",
        "back": "Greece",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Vad talar du för språk?",
        "back": "What languages do you speak?",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "vad ... för",
        "back": "what",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "tala (talar, talade, talat)",
        "back": "speak",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "grekiska",
        "back": "Greek",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "engelska",
        "back": "English",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "fråga (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "ask",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "varandra",
        "back": "each other",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "om",
        "back": "about",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "presentation (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "presentation",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Hej!",
        "back": "Hi!",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Turkiet",
        "back": "Turkey",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Spanien",
        "back": "Spain",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "nej",
        "back": "no",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "spanska",
        "back": "Spanish",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "lite",
        "back": "some, a little",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Brasilien",
        "back": "Brazil",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "jaha",
        "back": "I see",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "portugisiska",
        "back": "Portuguese",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "så klart",
        "back": "of course",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Du då?",
        "back": "How about you?",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Franska (-n)",
        "back": "French",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "pyttelite",
        "back": "a tiny bit",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Turkiska (-n)",
        "back": "Turkish",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "förstå (förstår, förstod, förstått)",
        "back": "understand",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "vad bra",
        "back": "that's great",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Trevligt att träffas!",
        "back": "Nice to meet you!",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Tartu",
        "back": "Tartu",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "var",
        "back": "where",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "ligga (ligger, låg, legat)",
        "back": "lie / be situated",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "i",
        "back": "in",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Estland",
        "back": "Estonia",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "okej",
        "back": "okay / OK",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Frankrike",
        "back": "France",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "lyssna (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "listen",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "dialog (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "dialogue",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "vilken (vilket, vilka)",
        "back": "which",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "ha (har, hade, haft)",
        "back": "have",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "betoning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "emphasis",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "ringa in",
        "back": "circle",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "igen",
        "back": "again",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "uttala (-ar, -de, -t)",
        "back": "pronounce",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "inte",
        "back": "not",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "markera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "mark",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "läsa (-er, -te, -t)",
        "back": "read",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "öva (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "practice",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "verb (-et, –, -en)",
        "back": "verb",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "ordföljd (-en)",
        "back": "word order",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "subjekt (-et, –, -en)",
        "back": "subject",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "fokus (-et, –)",
        "back": "focus",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "position (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "position",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "fundament (-et, –, -en)",
        "back": "sentence initial position",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "påstående (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "statement",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "före",
        "back": "before",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "efter",
        "back": "after",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "fråga (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "question",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "frågeord (-et, –, -en)",
        "back": "question words",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "ja- och nej-fråga (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "yes/no question",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Kanada",
        "back": "Canada",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "grupp (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "group",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "mingla (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "mingle",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Iran",
        "back": "Iran",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "presentera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "introduce",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "hon",
        "back": "she",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "han",
        "back": "he",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "den",
        "back": "it",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "det",
        "back": "it",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "vi",
        "back": "we",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "ni",
        "back": "you (plural)",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "de",
        "back": "they",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "subjektspronomen",
        "back": "subject pronoun",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "pronomen (-et, –, -en)",
        "back": "pronoun",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "jobba (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "work",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "med",
        "back": "with",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "vid",
        "back": "by",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "rätt (-a)",
        "back": "correct / right",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "bild (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "picture",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "läkare (-n, –, läkarna)",
        "back": "doctor",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "polis (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "police officer",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "servitör (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "waiter / waitress",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "advokat (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "lawyer",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "ingenjör (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "engineer",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "kock (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "chef",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "tandläkare (-n, –, tandläkarna)",
        "back": "dentist",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "frisör (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "hairdresser",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "webbdesigner (-n, webbdesigner, webbdesignerna)",
        "back": "web designer",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "sjuksköterska (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "nurse",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "pensionär (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "retiree",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "programmerare (-n, –, programmerarna)",
        "back": "programmer",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "kafé (-et, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "café",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Lycka till!",
        "back": "Good luck!",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "rekrytering (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "recruitment",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Vad kul!",
        "back": "How fun!",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "startup",
        "back": "startup",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "plugga (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "study",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "jobba extra",
        "back": "work part-time",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "mening (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "sentence",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "universitet (-et, –, -en)",
        "back": "university",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "gift (–, -a)",
        "back": "married",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "sambo (-n, -r, -rna)",
        "back": "live-in partner",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "singel",
        "back": "single",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "partner (-n, –, -na)",
        "back": "partner",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "barn (-et, –, -en)",
        "back": "child",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "son (-en, söner, sönerna)",
        "back": "son",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "dotter (-n, döttrar, döttrarna)",
        "back": "daughter",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "pojkvän (-nen, -ner, -nerna)",
        "back": "boyfriend",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "bo ihop",
        "back": "live together",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "bo (-r, bodde, bott)",
        "back": "live",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "ungefär",
        "back": "about / approximately",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "gifta sig (-er, -e, gift)",
        "back": "get married",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "skilja sig (-er, skilde, skilt)",
        "back": "get divorced",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "år (-et, –, -en)",
        "back": "year",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "person (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "person",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "man (-nen, män, männen)",
        "back": "man / husband",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "kvinna (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "woman",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "fru (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "wife",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "pojke (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "boy",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "flicka (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "girl",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "katt (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "cat",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "översätta (-er, -satte, -satt)",
        "back": "translate",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "alfabet (-et, –, -en)",
        "back": "alphabet",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "efternamn (-et, –, -en)",
        "back": "last name",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "stava (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "spell",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "bank (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "bank",
        "chapter": "Chapter1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Tjena!",
        "back": "Hi!",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "Hur mår du?",
        "back": "How are you?",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "må (mår, mådde, mått)",
        "back": "feel",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "bra",
        "back": "fine, well",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "bara bra",
        "back": "I'm fine, well",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "tack",
        "back": "thank you",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "Hur är läget?",
        "back": "How are things? / How's it going?",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "läge (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "situation",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "Det är lugnt.",
        "back": "Great. / Okay.",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "lugn (-t, -a)",
        "back": "cool, calm",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "Själv då?",
        "back": "How about you? / And you?",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "själv (-a)",
        "back": "self (myself, yourself, etc.)",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "Det är fint!",
        "back": "It's fine!",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "Allt bra med dig?",
        "back": "How are you? / How are things with you?",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "Ja, absolut!",
        "back": "Yes, definitely! / Of course!",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "Tja! (= Tjena!)",
        "back": "Hey! / Hi!",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "Hur är det med dig?",
        "back": "How are you?",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "riktigt",
        "back": "really",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "faktiskt",
        "back": "actually",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "Jo, det är okej.",
        "back": "Well, it's okay.",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "Det är mycket på jobbet.",
        "back": "There's a lot going on at work.",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "Nja, sådär.",
        "back": "Well, so-so.",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "God morgon!",
        "back": "Good morning!",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "Nja, inget vidare.",
        "back": "Well, not great.",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "jättetrött",
        "back": "really tired",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "Oj då!",
        "back": "Oh!",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "dricka (-er, drack, druckit)",
        "back": "drink",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "lite",
        "back": "a little, a bit",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "kaffe (-et)",
        "back": "coffee",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "jobbig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "tough",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "hoppas",
        "back": "hope",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "Jag är förkyld.",
        "back": "I have a cold.",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "åh",
        "back": "oh",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "Krya på dig!",
        "back": "Get well!",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "intonation (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "intonation",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "slut (-et, –, -en)",
        "back": "end",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "fras (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "phrase",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "gå (-r, gick, gått)",
        "back": "go",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "ton (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "pitch",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "upp",
        "back": "up",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "ner",
        "back": "down",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "placera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "place",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "här",
        "back": "here",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "nedanför",
        "back": "below",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "hälsa (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "greet",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "annan (annat, andra)",
        "back": "another",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "retur (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "return",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "pepp (-et, –, -en)",
        "back": "pep",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "Ta hand om dig!",
        "back": "Take care!",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "längta (-r, -de, -t) efter",
        "back": "long for, yearn for",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "i sommar",
        "back": "this summer",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "intresserad av",
        "back": "interested in",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "deckare (-n, –, deckarna)",
        "back": "crime novel",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "jazz (-en)",
        "back": "jazz",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "it-ingenjör (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "IT engineer",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "Syrien",
        "back": "Syria",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "kvällskurs (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "evening course",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "arkitektur (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "architecture",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "trivas (trivs, trivdes, trivts)",
        "back": "thrive, be happy",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "mormor (mormodern, mormödrar, mormödrarna)",
        "back": "grandmother (maternal)",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "morfar (morfadern, morfäder, morfäderna)",
        "back": "grandfather (maternal)",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "tillsammans",
        "back": "together",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "sport",
        "back": "sport",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "träna (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "exercise",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "karate",
        "back": "karate",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "sportig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "athletic",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "åka snowboard",
        "back": "go snowboarding",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "på vintern",
        "back": "in the winter",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "spela volleyboll",
        "back": "play volleyball",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "sol (-en)",
        "back": "sun",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "värme (-n)",
        "back": "warmth",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "mat (-en)",
        "back": "food",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "huvudsats (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "main clause",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "konjunktion (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "conjunction",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "så",
        "back": "so",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "stryka (stryker, strök, strukit) under",
        "back": "underline",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "fest (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "party",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "vän (-nen, -ner, -nerna)",
        "back": "friend",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    },
    {
        "front": "klasskompis (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "classmate",
        "chapter": "Chapter2"
    }
,
    {
        "front": "r\u00e4kna (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "count",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "siffra (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "digit, number",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "plats (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "place",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "kasta (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "throw, roll",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "t\u00e4rning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "dice",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "minus",
        "back": "minus",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "nummer (numret, \u2013, numren)",
        "back": "number",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "gata (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "street",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "hur m\u00e5nga",
        "back": "how many",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "telefonnummer (telefonnumret, \u2013, telefonnumren)",
        "back": "telephone number",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "ringa (-er, -de, -t)",
        "back": "call",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "i morgon",
        "back": "tomorrow",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "Vilket \u00e5r \u00e4r du f\u00f6dd?",
        "back": "What year were you born?",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6dd (-tt, -dda)",
        "back": "born",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "gammal (-t, -a)",
        "back": "old",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "fika (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "have a coffee",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "hur mycket",
        "back": "how much",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "ungef\u00e4r",
        "back": "about, approximately",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "skostorlek (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "shoe size",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "grad (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "degree",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "tal (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "number",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "Hur mycket \u00e4r klockan?",
        "back": "What time is it?",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "Hon/Den \u00e4r ...",
        "back": "It is ...",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "klocka (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "watch, clock",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "halv sju",
        "back": "six thirty",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "halv (-t, -a)",
        "back": "half",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6ver",
        "back": "over",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "kvart i",
        "back": "quarter to",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "kvart (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "quarter",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "prick (precis)",
        "back": "exactly",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "sekund (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "second",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "minut (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "minute",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "halvtimme (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "half an hour",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "timme (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "hour",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "b\u00e5t (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "boat",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "fem i",
        "back": "five to",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "fem \u00f6ver",
        "back": "five past",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "kvart \u00f6ver",
        "back": "quarter past",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "fem \u00f6ver halv",
        "back": "thirty-five past",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "skrift (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "writing",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "p\u00e5 morgonen",
        "back": "in the morning",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "p\u00e5 kv\u00e4llen",
        "back": "in the evening",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "p\u00e5 f\u00f6rmiddagen",
        "back": "before noon",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "p\u00e5 eftermiddagen",
        "back": "in the afternoon",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "p\u00e5 natten",
        "back": "at night",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "fika (-t) (vard)",
        "back": "coffee break",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "yogal\u00e4ger (l\u00e4gret, \u2013, l\u00e4gren)",
        "back": "yoga retreat",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "n\u00e4sta vecka",
        "back": "next week",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "program (-met, \u2013, -men)",
        "back": "program",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "vilken tid",
        "back": "what time",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "b\u00f6rja (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "begin",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rst",
        "back": "first",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6rtte (-t, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "herbal tea",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "koffein (-et)",
        "back": "caffeine",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00c5 gud!",
        "back": "Oh God!",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "snabbkaffe (-t)",
        "back": "instant coffee",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "lunch (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "lunch",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "hur dags",
        "back": "what time",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "servera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "serve",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "vegansk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "vegan",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "kaffe p\u00e5 maten",
        "back": "coffee after the meal",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "paus (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "break, pause",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "sista",
        "back": "last, final",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "sluta (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "end",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "Det l\u00e5ter bra!",
        "back": "That sounds good.",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "fikapaus (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "coffee break",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "frukost (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "breakfast",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "mellanm\u00e5l (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "light snack",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "middag (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "dinner",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "hem (-met, \u2013, -men)",
        "back": "home",
        "chapter": "Chapter3"
    },
    {
        "front": "favoritfik (et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "favourite caf\u00e9, favourite coffee shop",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "ofta",
        "back": "often",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e4lska (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "love",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "favoritplats (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "favourite place",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "glad (glatt, glada)",
        "back": "happy",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "stund (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "moment",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "bagare (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "baker",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "baka (-r, -ade, -ade)",
        "back": "bake",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "fikabr\u00f6d (et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "pastries",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "ut",
        "back": "out",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "provsmaka (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "taste, sample",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "bulle (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "roll, bun",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "kaka (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "cookie, biscuit",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "sm\u00f6rg\u00e5s (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "sandwich",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "kardemummabulle (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "cardamom bun, cardamom roll",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "semla (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "semla, Swedish cream bun",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "allt",
        "back": "everything",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "god (gott, goda)",
        "back": "good",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "ligga (-er, l\u00e5g, legat)",
        "back": "be located",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "hj\u00e4lpa (-er, hj\u00e4lpte, hj\u00e4lpt)",
        "back": "help",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6lja med",
        "back": "join in, come along",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "g\u00e4rna",
        "back": "happily, willingly",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e4nge",
        "back": "a long time, long",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "sak (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "thing",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "stackars",
        "back": "poor, unfortunate",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "d\u00e5",
        "back": "then",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "bara",
        "back": "only",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "snus (-et)",
        "back": "snuff",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "livs",
        "back": "grocery store",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "perfekt (-a)",
        "back": "perfect",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "wienerbr\u00f6d (-et, -en, -ena)",
        "back": "Danish pastry",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "hj\u00e4lpverb (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "helping verbs, auxiliary verbs",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "infinitiv (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "infinitive",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "ska",
        "back": "will",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "vilja (vill, ville, velat)",
        "back": "want",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "satsadverbial (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "adverbial",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "handla (-r, -ade, -at)",
        "back": "shop, buy",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "skulle vilja",
        "back": "would like to",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "Var det bra s\u00e5?",
        "back": "Will that be all?",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "Kan jag f\u00e5 ...?",
        "back": "Can I have ...?",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "javissst",
        "back": "yes, of course",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "vars\u00e5god",
        "back": "you\u2019re welcome",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "N\u00e5got annat?",
        "back": "Anything else?",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "nej tack",
        "back": "no thank you",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "Det var bra s\u00e5.",
        "back": "That is all.",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "Det blir ... kronor.",
        "back": "That comes to ... kronor.",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "krona (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "crown",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "blippa (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "tap, scan",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "kort (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "card",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "Vill du ha ...?",
        "back": "Do you want ...?",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "kvitto (-t, -on, -ona)",
        "back": "receipt",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "latte",
        "back": "latte",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "liten (litet, sm\u00e5)",
        "back": "small",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "mellan",
        "back": "medium",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "ostsm\u00f6rg\u00e5s (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "cheese sandwich",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "ost (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "cheese",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "precis",
        "back": "exactly",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "kosta (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "cost",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "mer",
        "back": "more",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "strax",
        "back": "soon",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "Tar ni kontanter?",
        "back": "Do you accept cash?",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "tyv\u00e4rr",
        "back": "unfortunately",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "inga problem",
        "back": "no problem",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "betala (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "pay",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "toppen",
        "back": "super, great",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "demonstrativa pronomen",
        "back": "demonstrative pronouns",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "n\u00e4r",
        "back": "when",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "peka (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "point",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "n\u00e4ra",
        "back": "near, close to",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "en bit bort",
        "back": "a short distance away",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "kontrollera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "check, control",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00f6k",
        "back": "find, search",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "bild (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "picture",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "morotskaka (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "carrot cake",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "chokladboll (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "chocolate ball",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "mazarin (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "almond pastry",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "dammsugare (-n, \u2013, -arna)",
        "back": "vacuum cleaner (pastry)",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "veganbrownie (-n, -s)",
        "back": "vegan brownie",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "brownie (-n, -s)",
        "back": "brownie",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "r\u00e4ksallad (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "shrimp salad",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "falafelsallad (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "falafel salad",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "ostpaj (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "cheese pie, cheese quiche",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "pizzabit (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "pizza slice",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "bryggkaffe (-t)",
        "back": "brewed coffee",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "glas (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "glass",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e4sk (= l\u00e4skedryck) (-en)",
        "back": "soft drink, fizzy drink",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "p\u00e4ron (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "pear",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "paket (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "package",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "sammansatta ord",
        "back": "compound words",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "flera",
        "back": "several",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rsta",
        "back": "first",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "snusdosa (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "snuff box",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "bokstav (-en, bokst\u00e4ver, bokst\u00e4verna)",
        "back": "letter",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "gurka (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "cucumber",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "druva / vindruva (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "grape",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "purjol\u00f6k (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "leek",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "citron (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "lemon",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e4gg (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "egg",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "plural",
        "back": "plural",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "sko (-n, -r, -rna)",
        "back": "shoe",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "bakelse (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "pastry",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "saffransbulle (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "saffron bun",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "mango (-n, -r)",
        "back": "mango",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "mataff\u00e4r (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "grocery store",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "hylla (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "shelf",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "till v\u00e4nster",
        "back": "to the left",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "till h\u00f6ger",
        "back": "to the right",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "rakt fram",
        "back": "straight ahead",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "andra",
        "back": "second",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "tredje",
        "back": "third",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "fj\u00e4rde",
        "back": "fourth",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "femte",
        "back": "fifth",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "frukt och gr\u00f6nt",
        "back": "fruit and vegetable section",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "frukt (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "fruit",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "gr\u00f6n (-t, -a)",
        "back": "green",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "mejeri (-et, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "dairy",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "fisk (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "fish",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "skaldjur (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "she",
        "chapter": "Chapter4"
    },
    {
        "front": "Ska vi g\u00e5 p\u00e5 ...?",
        "back": "Shall we go to ...?",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "bio (-n)",
        "back": "cinema",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "biograf (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "cinema",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "fredag (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "Friday",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00e4nga med",
        "back": "join in",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "Vad ska ni se?",
        "back": "What are you going to see?",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "semester (-n, -rar, -rarna)",
        "back": "vacation, holiday",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "helvete (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "hell",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "skr\u00e4ckfilm (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "horror movie",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "komedi (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "comedy",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e5ta (-er, l\u00e4t, l\u00e5tit)",
        "back": "sound",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "Var g\u00e5r den?",
        "back": "Where does it play?",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "Den b\u00f6rjar klockan ...",
        "back": "It starts at ...",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "ta ett glas ...",
        "back": "have a glass of ...",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "Ja, sj\u00e4lvklart!",
        "back": "Yes, of course!",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "Inget speciellt.",
        "back": "Nothing special.",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "Hur s\u00e5?",
        "back": "How so?",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "biljett (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "ticket",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "dr\u00f6mspel (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "dream play",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "huvudroll (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "leading role, main role",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "lust (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "desire",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "favorit (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "favorite",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "inte direkt",
        "back": "not really",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "Vad synd!",
        "back": "Too bad!",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "i st\u00e4llet",
        "back": "instead",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "st\u00e5upp",
        "back": "stand-up comedy",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "kosta (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "cost",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "intr\u00e4de (-t, \u2013, -n)",
        "back": "admission",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "ses (ses, s\u00e5gs, setts)",
        "back": "meet",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "slutspel (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "playoffs",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "mot",
        "back": "against",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "Grejt!",
        "back": "Great!",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "fixa (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "sort out, buy",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "veckodag (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "weekday",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00e5ndag (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "Monday",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "tisdag (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "Tuesday",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "onsdag (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "Wednesday",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "torsdag (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "Thursday",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00f6rdag (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "Saturday",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00f6ndag (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "Sunday",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "pj\u00e4s (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "play",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "citat (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "quote, quotation",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "synd om",
        "back": "pity",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00e4nniska (-n, m\u00e4nniskor, m\u00e4nniskorna)",
        "back": "human, person",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "annons (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "advertisement",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "dansa (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "dance",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "sjunga (-er, sj\u00f6ng, sjungit)",
        "back": "sing",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "framtid (-en)",
        "back": "future",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "i kv\u00e4ll",
        "back": "tonight",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "i morgon",
        "back": "tomorrow",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "positiv (-t, -a)",
        "back": "positive",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "negativ (-t, -a)",
        "back": "negative",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "best\u00e4mma (-er, -de, -t)",
        "back": "decide",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "presens futurum",
        "back": "future tense",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "squash (-en)",
        "back": "squash",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "slappa (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "relax",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "Vad g\u00f6r du p\u00e5 fritiden?",
        "back": "What do you do in your free time?",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "fritid (-en)",
        "back": "free time, spare time",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "korrekt (-a)",
        "back": "correct",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6vning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "exercise",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "forts\u00e4tta (-er, fortsatte, fortsatt)",
        "back": "continue",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00e4nga (-er, -de, -t)",
        "back": "hang out",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "kl\u00e4ttra (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "climb",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "skejta (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "skate",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "kl\u00e4ttring (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "climbing",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "bruka (-r, -ade, har brukat)",
        "back": "usually",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "serie (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "series",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "familj (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "family",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "p\u00e5 landet",
        "back": "in the countryside",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "d\u00e4r",
        "back": "there",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "mysa (-er, -te, -t)",
        "back": "cozy up",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "br\u00e4dspel (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "board game",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "kolla (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "watch",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "dataspel (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "video game",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "hund (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "dog",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "g\u00f6ra trick",
        "back": "do tricks",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "bowla (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "bowl",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "ta en AW",
        "back": "go for after-work drinks",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "promenera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "walk",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "park (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "park",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "skrattyoga (-n)",
        "back": "laughter yoga",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "tr\u00e4dg\u00e5rd (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "garden",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "blomma (-n, blommor, blommorna)",
        "back": "flower",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "gr\u00f6nsak (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "vegetable",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "b\u00e4r (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "berries",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00f6na (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "hen",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00e5 (-r, fick, f\u00e5tt)",
        "back": "get",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "superekologisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "ultra-organic",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "ekologisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "organic",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "loppis (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "flea market",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e5ka runt",
        "back": "drive around",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "auktion (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "auction",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "samla (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "collect",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "jaga (-r, -ade, -t)",
        "back": "hunt",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "fiska (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "fish",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "bibliotek (-et, -en, -ena)",
        "back": "library",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "aldrig",
        "back": "never",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "ibland",
        "back": "sometimes",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "vid havet",
        "back": "by the sea, at the seaside",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "bada (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "swim",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "spela (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "play",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "boule",
        "back": "boules",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "paraplydrink (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "umbrella drink",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00e4rlig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "lovely",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6r",
        "back": "because",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "fler saker",
        "back": "more things",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "fotboll (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "football, soccer",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "innebandy (-n)",
        "back": "floorball",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "hockey (-n)",
        "back": "ice hockey",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "spela kort",
        "back": "play cards",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "trumpet (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "trumpet",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "skida (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "ski",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "skridsko (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "skate",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "skejtboard (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "skateboard",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "inlines",
        "back": "inline skates, rollerblades",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "natur (-en)",
        "back": "nature",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "kyrka (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "church",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "mosk\u00e9",
        "back": "mosque",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "synagoga",
        "back": "synagogue",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "tempel",
        "back": "temple",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "teater (-n, teatrar, teatrarna)",
        "back": "theater",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "opera (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "opera",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "konsert (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "concert",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "klubb (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "club",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "festival (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "festival",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "bar (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "bar",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "match (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "match, game",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "adverbial",
        "back": "adverbial",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00e4llan",
        "back": "rarely",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "alltid",
        "back": "always",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "fundamentposition",
        "back": "initial position",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "tidsadverbial",
        "back": "temporal adverbial",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "frekvens (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "frequency",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "hobby (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "hobby",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "laga mat",
        "back": "cook",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "polisserie (-n, -r, -rna)",
        "back": "cop show, crime drama series",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "Vilken ... ska vi se?",
        "back": "Which ... should we watch?",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "framf\u00f6r",
        "back": "in front of",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "streamingtj\u00e4nst (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "streaming service",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "romantisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "romantic",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "historisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "historical",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "klassisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "classical, classic",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e4skig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "scary",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "handla om",
        "back": "it is about",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "hitta (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "find",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00e4rlek (-en, -er, -arna)",
        "back": "love",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "efter\u00e5t",
        "back": "afterwards",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "Det blir bra!",
        "back": "Fine!",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "adjektiv (-en)",
        "back": "adjective",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "grundform (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "infinitive form",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "inom parentes",
        "back": "in parentheses",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "dokument\u00e4r (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "documentary",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "konst (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "art",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "tr\u00e5kig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "boring",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "fantastisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "fantastic",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "bakning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "baking",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "d\u00e5lig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "bad, ill",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "sorglig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "sad",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "sv\u00e5r (-t, -a)",
        "back": "difficult",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "Vad gillar du f\u00f6r ...?",
        "back": "What kind of ... do you like?",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "japansk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Japanese",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "genre (-n, -r, -rna)",
        "back": "genre",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "actionfilm (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "action movie",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "science fiction",
        "back": "science fiction",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "drama (-t, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "drama",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "rysare (-en, \u2013, -arna)",
        "back": "thriller, horror",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "n\u00e5gra g\u00e5nger",
        "back": "few times",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "forskare (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "researcher",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "forska (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "do research",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "bioteknik (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "biotechnology",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "hans",
        "back": "his",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "Gamla stan",
        "back": "Old Town",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "Lutande tornet",
        "back": "The Leaning Tower of Pisa",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "vakna av",
        "back": "wake up from",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "duva (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "pigeon, dove",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "sitta (-er, satt, suttit)",
        "back": "sit",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "p\u00e5 taket",
        "back": "on the roof",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "g\u00e5 upp",
        "back": "go up",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00f6rn (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "corner",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "skorpa (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "rusk",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "kaf\u00e9\u00e4gare (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "caf\u00e9 owner",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4der (v\u00e4dret, v\u00e4der, v\u00e4dren)",
        "back": "weather",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "politik (-en)",
        "back": "politics",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "semesterplan (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "holiday plan",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "stad (-en, st\u00e4der, st\u00e4derna)",
        "back": "city, town",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00f6te (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "meeting",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "undervisa (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "teach",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "speciell (-t, -a)",
        "back": "special",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "turist (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "tourist",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "videom\u00f6te (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "video meeting",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "USA",
        "back": "USA",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "st\u00e4nga av",
        "back": "shut off",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "springa (-er, sprang, sprungit)",
        "back": "run",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "vid floden",
        "back": "by the river",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "middag (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "dinner",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "p\u00e5 v\u00e4gen hem",
        "back": "on the way home",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00e5ne (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "moon",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "sent p\u00e5 kv\u00e4llen",
        "back": "late in the evening",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "flytta (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "move",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "preteritum",
        "back": "past tense",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "special",
        "back": "special",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "byta ut",
        "back": "replace",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "vampyr (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "vampire",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rkyld (-t, -a)",
        "back": "have a cold",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "meny (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "menu",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "ny (nytt, nya)",
        "back": "new",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "yrke (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "profession",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "ekonomi (-n)",
        "back": "accounts, economics",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "tema (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "theme",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "ung (-t, -a)",
        "back": "young",
        "chapter": "Chapter5"
    },
    {
        "front": "sl\u00e4kt (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "relatives",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "syskon (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "sibling",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "bror (-n, br\u00f6der, br\u00f6derna)",
        "back": "brother",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rskola (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "preschool",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "personlig tr\u00e4nare",
        "back": "personal trainer",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "b\u00e5da",
        "back": "both",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "sv\u00e4gerska (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "sister-in-law",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00e4nna (-er, -de, -t)",
        "back": "know",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "syskonbarn (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "niece/nephew",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "egen",
        "back": "own",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "bonusbarn (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "stepchild",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4ldigt mycket",
        "back": "very much",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6r\u00e4lder (-n, f\u00f6r\u00e4ldrar, f\u00f6r\u00e4ldrarna)",
        "back": "parent",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "omgift (-, -a)",
        "back": "remarried",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "plastmamma (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "stepmother",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "plastikkirurg (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "plastic surgeon",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "privat (-, -a)",
        "back": "private",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "klinik (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "clinic",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "stepbonussyskon (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "step-siblings",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00e5nga",
        "back": "many",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "halvsyskon (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "half-sibling",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "g\u00e5ng (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "time",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00e5 barn",
        "back": "have children, have a child",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "syster (-n, systrar, systrarna)",
        "back": "sister",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "moster (-n, mostrar, mostrarna)",
        "back": "aunt (maternal)",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "gifta sig (-er, -e, gift)",
        "back": "get married",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "fransman (-nen, fransm\u00e4n, fransm\u00e4nnen)",
        "back": "Frenchman",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "professor (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "professor",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00e4rnteknik (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "nuclear technology",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "kusin (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "cousin",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "ungef\u00e4r",
        "back": "about, approximately",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "p\u00e5 min pappas sida",
        "back": "on my father's side",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "ha mycket kontakt",
        "back": "have a lot of contact, be in close contact",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "alla",
        "back": "everyone",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "barnbarn (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "grandchildren",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "bonusbarnbarn",
        "back": "step-grandchild",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "barnbarnsbarn",
        "back": "great-grandchild",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "sl\u00e4kting (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "relative",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "sk\u00e5despelare (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "actor",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "farbror (farbrodern, farbr\u00f6der, farbr\u00f6derna)",
        "back": "uncle (paternal)",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "sj\u00f6kapten (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "sea captain, ship captain",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "morfarsfar (-n, morfarsf\u00e4der, morfarsf\u00e4derna)",
        "back": "maternal great-grandfather",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "konstn\u00e4r (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "artist",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "faster (-n, fastrar, fastrarna)",
        "back": "aunt (paternal)",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "Nobelpriset",
        "back": "the Nobel Prize",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "kemi (-n)",
        "back": "chemistry",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "familjeord (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "family-related words",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "pappa (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "dad, father",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "far (-n, f\u00e4der, f\u00e4derna)",
        "back": "father",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "mamma (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "mom, mother",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "mor (-n, m\u00f6drar, m\u00f6drarna)",
        "back": "mother",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "sl\u00e4kttr\u00e4d (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "family tree",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "passa in (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "fit in",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "dotter (-n, d\u00f6ttrar, d\u00f6ttrarna)",
        "back": "daughter",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "separera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "separate",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "relation (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "relationship",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "familjemedlem (-men, -mar, -marna)",
        "back": "family member",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e5tsassyskon (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "step-sibling",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "extrapappa (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "extra dad, bonus dad",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "relativt pronomen",
        "back": "relative pronoun",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "Australien",
        "back": "Australia",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "psykolog (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "psychologist",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "g\u00e5 i skolan",
        "back": "go to school",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "skola (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "school",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "yogainstrukt\u00f6r (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "yoga instructor",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "piano (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "piano",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "Jaha, wow!",
        "back": "I see, wow!",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "ju",
        "back": "you know",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "flytta (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "move",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "Polen",
        "back": "Poland",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "Finland",
        "back": "Finland",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "i helgen",
        "back": "this weekend",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "helg (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "weekend",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "Gotland",
        "back": "Gotland, island in the Baltic",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "Jaha, vad trevligt!",
        "back": "I see, that's nice!",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "hos",
        "back": "at",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "possessiva pronomen",
        "back": "possessive pronouns",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "min (mitt, mina)",
        "back": "my",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "din (ditt, dina)",
        "back": "your",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "hennes",
        "back": "her",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "hen",
        "back": "they/them",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "hens",
        "back": "their",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "dess",
        "back": "its",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "de",
        "back": "they",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e5r (-t, -a)",
        "back": "our",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "er (-t, -a)",
        "back": "your",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "deras",
        "back": "their",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "kvadratmeter (-n, \u2013, kvadratmetrarna)",
        "back": "square meters",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "sakna (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "miss",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "Indien",
        "back": "India",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "korean",
        "back": "Korean",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "Sydkorea",
        "back": "South Korea",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "inga",
        "back": "no",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "ensam (-t, ensamma)",
        "back": "alone",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "hus (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "house",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "Nobelpristagare (-n, \u2013, -arna)",
        "back": "Nobel prize winner",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "i m\u00e5ndags",
        "back": "last Monday",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "stadshus (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "city hall",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00c4r det sant?",
        "back": "Is it true? Really?",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "Nobelfesten",
        "back": "the Nobel Banquet",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "pris (-et, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "prize",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "Coolt, va?",
        "back": "Cool, right? Isn't it cool?",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "cool (-t, -a)",
        "back": "cool",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "verkligen",
        "back": "really",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "examen (\u2013, examina)",
        "back": "degree",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "molekyl (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "molecule",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "luktsinne",
        "back": "sense of smell",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "forskningsstipendium (-et, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "research grant",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "sp\u00e4nnande",
        "back": "exciting, suspenseful",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "kemil\u00e4xa",
        "back": "chemistry homework",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e4xa (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "homework",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "i h\u00f6stas",
        "back": "last fall, autumn",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00f6ra (h\u00f6r, h\u00f6rde, h\u00f6rt)",
        "back": "hear",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "otrolig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "incredible",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "massa (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "a lot",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "sl\u00e4ktmiddag (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "extended family dinner",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "i l\u00f6rdags",
        "back": "last Saturday",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "j\u00e4ttekul",
        "back": "a lot of fun",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "j\u00e4ttetrevlig",
        "back": "really nice",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "prisutdelning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "award ceremony",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "kung (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "king",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "inte precis",
        "back": "not exactly",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "se (-r, s\u00e5g, sett)",
        "back": "see",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "objektspronomen",
        "back": "object pronoun",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "mig",
        "back": "me",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "dig",
        "back": "you",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "honom",
        "back": "him",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "henne",
        "back": "her",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "den/det",
        "back": "it",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "oss",
        "back": "us",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "er",
        "back": "you",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "dem",
        "back": "them",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "Vilka objektspronomen st\u00e5r tillsammans med fraserna i rutan?",
        "back": "Which object pronouns are used with the phrases in the box?",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "bil (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "car",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "vacker (-t, -vackra)",
        "back": "beautiful",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "dynamit (-en)",
        "back": "dynamite",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "december",
        "back": "December",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "d\u00f6 (-r, dog, -tt)",
        "back": "die",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "kemist (-en, -en, -erna)",
        "back": "chemist",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "uppfinnare (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "inventor",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "ogift",
        "back": "unmarried, single",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "testamente (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "will",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "fysik (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "physics",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "litteratur (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "literature",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "fred (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "peace",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "dela (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "share, give out",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "kronprins (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "crown prince",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "fredspris (-et)",
        "back": "peace prize",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6das (-, f\u00f6ds, f\u00f6ddes, f\u00f6tts)",
        "back": "be born",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "arkitekt (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "architect",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "vapenkonstrukt\u00f6r (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "weapons engineer",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "ekonomisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "economic",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "problem (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "problem",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "Ryssland",
        "back": "Russia",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "filosofi (-n)",
        "back": "philosophy",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "ryska (-n)",
        "back": "Russian",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "tyska (-n)",
        "back": "German",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rfattare (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "author, writer",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "17-\u00e5ring (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "17-year-old",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "g\u00f6ra (g\u00f6r, gjorde, gjort)",
        "back": "do, make",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "studieresa (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "study trip",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "Europa",
        "back": "Europe",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "komma i kontakt med",
        "back": "get in touch with",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "nitroglycerin (-en, \u2013, -et)",
        "back": "nitroglycerin",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "aff\u00e4r (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "business",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "experimentera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "experiment",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "explosion (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "explosion",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "bygga (-er, -de, -t)",
        "back": "build",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "fabrik (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "factory",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "arbete (-t, -n, -ena)",
        "back": "work",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "patent (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "patent",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "tj\u00e4na (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "earn",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "tj\u00e4na pengar",
        "back": "earn money",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e4ga (-er, \u00e4gde, \u00e4gt)",
        "back": "own",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "resa (-er, -te, -t)",
        "back": "travel",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "miljon (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "million",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "i dagens v\u00e4rde",
        "back": "in today's value",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "viktig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "important",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "man trodde",
        "back": "it was believed, people believed",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "gruva (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "mine",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "tunnel (-n, -tunnlar, tunnlarna)",
        "back": "tunnel",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4g (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "road",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "j\u00e4rnv\u00e4g (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "railway",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "bomb (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "bomb",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "vapen (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "weapon",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "krig (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "war",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "fredsaktivist (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "peace activist",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rbjuda (-er, f\u00f6rbj\u00f6d, f\u00f6rbjudit)",
        "back": "ban, prohibit",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "stoppa (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "stop",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "eftersom",
        "back": "because",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "farlig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "dangerous",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "inspirera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "inspire",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "skriva in (-er, skrev, skrivit)",
        "back": "include",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "morbror (morbroder, morbr\u00f6der, morbr\u00f6derna)",
        "back": "uncle (maternal)",
        "chapter": "Chapter6"
    },
    {
        "front": "intervjua (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "interview",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "shopping (-en)",
        "back": "shopping",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "doftljus (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "scented candle",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "krukv\u00e4xt (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "potted plant",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "orkid\u00e9 (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "orchid",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "gardin (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "curtain",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "vit (-t, -a)",
        "back": "white",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ljusgr\u00e5 (-tt, -a)",
        "back": "light gray",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ha r\u00e5d",
        "back": "be able to afford",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00e5nad (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "month",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "kl\u00e4der (-na)",
        "back": "clothes",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "rea (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "sale",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rra m\u00e5naden",
        "back": "last month",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "halsduk (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "scarf",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "r\u00f6d (r\u00f6tt, -a)",
        "back": "red",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "handske (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "glove",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "tappa (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "lose",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "buss (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "bus",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "i g\u00e5r",
        "back": "yesterday",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "begagnad (-t, -e)",
        "back": "used, second-hand",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "sneakers",
        "back": "sneakers",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "redan",
        "back": "already",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "j\u00e4ttem\u00e5nga",
        "back": "a huge number",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "galen (-t, -a)",
        "back": "crazy",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "garderob (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "wardrobe, closet",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "full (-t, -a)",
        "back": "full",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "historisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "historical",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "kryssning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "cruise",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "Karibien",
        "back": "the Caribbean",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "spara (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "save",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "villa (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "villa, house",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rra \u00e5ret",
        "back": "last year",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00e4lja (-er, -de, -t)",
        "back": "sell",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ge bort (-r, gav, -tt)",
        "back": "give away",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "suddgummi (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "eraser",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "luktsuddgummi",
        "back": "scented eraser",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "jordgubbslukt",
        "back": "strawberry scent",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "jordgubbe (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "strawberry",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "lukt",
        "back": "scent, smell",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "husdjur (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "pet",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "p\u00e4lsdjur (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "furry animal",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "allergisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "allergic",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6dla (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "lizard",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "lego",
        "back": "LEGO",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "rum (-met, \u2013, -men)",
        "back": "room",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "tr\u00f6ttna (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "get tired of",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ge (-r, gav, -tt)",
        "back": "give",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "lillkusin (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "little cousin",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "cykel (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "bicycle, bike",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "mountainbike (-n, -s, -sen)",
        "back": "mountain bike",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "spela roll (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "matter",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "stycke (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "paragraph",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e5na (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "borrow",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "varuhus (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "department store",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00e4ng (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "bed",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "madrass (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "mattress",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "kudde (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "pillow",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "lakan (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "bedsheets",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "dunt\u00e4cke (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "down duvet",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00e4nglampa (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "bedside lamp",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "kastrull (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "saucepan",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "gryta (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "pot",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "sked (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "spoon",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "gaffel (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "fork",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "kniv (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "knife",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "flytta ihop",
        "back": "move in together",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00f6k (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "kitchen",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "avdelning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "department",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "Vad kan jag hj\u00e4lpa er med?",
        "back": "What can I help you with?",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "sova gott (-er, sov, -it)",
        "back": "sleep well",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "serie (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "series",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "popul\u00e4r (-t, -a)",
        "back": "popular",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "sk\u00f6n (-t, -a)",
        "back": "pleasant",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00e5rd (h\u00e5rt, -a)",
        "back": "hard",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "mjuk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "soft",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "pr\u00f6va (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "test",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "prinsessa (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "princess",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "90-s\u00e4ng (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "single bed",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "st\u00e4lla ihop (-er, -de, -t)",
        "back": "put together",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "dubbels\u00e4ng (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "double bed",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "Det l\u00e5ter bra.",
        "back": "That sounds good.",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "total (-t, -a)",
        "back": "total",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "dyr (-t, -a)",
        "back": "expensive",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "billig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "cheap",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "b\u00e4st (-a)",
        "back": "best",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "kvalitet (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "quality",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "garanti (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "guarantee",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "just nu",
        "back": "right now",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "erbjudande (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "offer",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "specialerbjudande",
        "back": "special offer",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "utan",
        "back": "without",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "extra kostnad",
        "back": "extra cost",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "egyptisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Egyptian",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "bomull (-en)",
        "back": "cotton",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "halva priset",
        "back": "half price",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "fundera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "think",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00f6ksgrejer",
        "back": "kitchen stuff",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00f6ksavdelning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "kitchen department",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "superfin (-t, -a)",
        "back": "super nice, very beautiful",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "pasta (-n)",
        "back": "pasta",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "snygg (-t, -a)",
        "back": "nice, attractive",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00f6ttf\u00e4rss\u00e5s (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "Bolognese",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "mellanstorlek (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "medium size",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "bestick (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "cutlery",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00e4r borta",
        "back": "over here",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "r\u00e4cka (-er, -te, -t)",
        "back": "be enough",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "Hur ska vi g\u00f6ra med ...?",
        "back": "What should we do about ...?",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "sova p\u00e5 saken",
        "back": "sleep on it",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "schema (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "schedule",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "j\u00e4mf\u00f6ra (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "compare",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "plagg (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "piece of clothing, garment",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ett par byxor",
        "back": "a pair of pants",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "jacka (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "jacket",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "trosor (-na)",
        "back": "women\u2019s underwear",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "kalsonger (-na)",
        "back": "men\u2019s underwear",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "kjol (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "skirt",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "slips (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "tie",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ett par skor",
        "back": "a pair of shoes",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "bh (-:n, -:ar, -:arna)",
        "back": "bra",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "kavaj (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "suit jacket",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "skjorta (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "shirt",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "stickad tr\u00f6ja (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "knitted sweater",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "strumpa (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "sock",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "linne (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "tank top, camisole",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "t-shirt (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "t-shirt",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "kappa (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "coat",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "kl\u00e4nning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "dress",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "kofta (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "cardigan",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "hoodie / luvtr\u00f6ja (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "hoodie",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "pyjamas (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "pyjamas",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00e4rg (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "color",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "monster (-ret, \u2013, -ren)",
        "back": "monster",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "bl\u00e5 (-tt, -a)",
        "back": "blue",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "vit (-t, -a)",
        "back": "white",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "gr\u00f6n (-t, -a)",
        "back": "green",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "gr\u00e5 (-tt, -a)",
        "back": "grey",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "orange (\u2013, -a)",
        "back": "orange",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "gul (-t, -a)",
        "back": "yellow",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "brun (-t, -a)",
        "back": "brown",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "svart (-a)",
        "back": "black",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "rosa",
        "back": "pink",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "prickig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "spotted, polka-dot",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "blommig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "floral",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "randig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "striped",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "rutig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "checkered",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00f6nstrad (-t, -e)",
        "back": "patterned",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "motsats (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "opposite",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "bred (brett, -a)",
        "back": "wide",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "tjock (-t, -a)",
        "back": "fat",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ljus (-t, -a)",
        "back": "light",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "modern (-t, -a)",
        "back": "modern",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "omodern (-t, -a)",
        "back": "outdated",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "smal (-t, -a)",
        "back": "thin",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ful (-t, -a)",
        "back": "ugly",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "Vad har du p\u00e5 dig i dag?",
        "back": "What are you wearing today?",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6ppet k\u00f6p",
        "back": "refund policy",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "Hur mycket f\u00e5r de kosta?",
        "back": "How much can they cost?",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "Passar de bra?",
        "back": "Do they fit well?",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "passa (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "fit",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "Hur mycket kostar den?",
        "back": "How much does it cost?",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "en storlek mindre",
        "back": "one size smaller",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "Vilken storlek har du?",
        "back": "What size are you?",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "Vill du ha hj\u00e4lp?",
        "back": "Would you like some help?",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "Kan jag hj\u00e4lpa till?",
        "back": "Can I help you?",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "prova (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "try",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ett \u00f6gonblick",
        "back": "one moment",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "provrum (-met, \u2013, -men)",
        "back": "fitting room",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6r stora",
        "back": "too large",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "bytesr\u00e4tt (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "right to exchange",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6gonskugga (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "eye shadow",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "d\u00e5 ska vi se",
        "back": "let\u2019s see",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "medlem (-men, -mar, -marna)",
        "back": "member",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "Jag tittar bara.",
        "back": "I\u2019m just looking.",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "S\u00e4g till om du beh\u00f6ver hj\u00e4lp.",
        "back": "Let me know if you need help.",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00f6parsko (-n, -r, -rna)",
        "back": "running shoe",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "Kan du hj\u00e4lpa mig?",
        "back": "Can you help me?",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "springa (-er, sprang, sprungit)",
        "back": "run",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "skog (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "forest",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "asfalt (-en)",
        "back": "asphalt",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00f6pband (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "treadmill",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "Sitter de bra?",
        "back": "Do they fit well?",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "konsumentfakta (-n)",
        "back": "consumer information",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e4mna tillbaka (-r, -ade, -t)",
        "back": "return",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "komparation",
        "back": "comparison",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "komparativ",
        "back": "comparative",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "superlativ",
        "back": "superlative",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "kort (-a)",
        "back": "short",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "t\u00e4lt (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "tent",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "prata engelska",
        "back": "speak English",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "Jag l\u00e4ser svenska.",
        "back": "I study Swedish.",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "tio",
        "back": "ten",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "liter (-n, litrar, litrarna)",
        "back": "liter",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "n\u00e4rbutik (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "local grocery store",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "herre (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "gentleman, man",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "gym (-met, \u2013, -men)",
        "back": "gym",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "skylt (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "sign",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00e5l (-en)",
        "back": "cabbage",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00e4r (-t, -a)",
        "back": "in love",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "sk\u00e5l (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "bowl",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "sk\u00e4r (-t, -a)",
        "back": "pink",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "sjuksk\u00f6terska (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "nurse",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00f6p (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "buy",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "resv\u00e4ska (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "suitcase",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e4tt (-a)",
        "back": "light",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "neongr\u00f6n (-t, -a)",
        "back": "neon green",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "bagage (-t, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "luggage",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "bagageband (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "baggage carousel",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "guld (-et)",
        "back": "gold",
        "chapter": "Chapter7"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rsta g\u00e5ngen",
        "back": "first time",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "Storbritannien",
        "back": "the United Kingdom",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "kultur (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "culture",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4der (v\u00e4dret, v\u00e4der, v\u00e4dren)",
        "back": "weather",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4derprognos (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "weather forecast",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4xlande v\u00e4der",
        "back": "changing weather",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "regn (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "rain",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "packa (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "pack",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "sommarkl\u00e4der",
        "back": "summer clothes",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "tr\u00e4ningskl\u00e4der",
        "back": "sportswear",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "regnjacka (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "raincoat",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "gummist\u00f6vel (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "rubber boot, Wellington boot",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "varm tr\u00f6ja (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "warm sweater",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "myggmedel (myggmedlet, \u2013, myggmedlen)",
        "back": "mosquito repellent",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rst\u00e5s",
        "back": "of course",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "juli",
        "back": "July",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "hemma hos",
        "back": "at the home of",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "forum (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "forum",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "mitt i stan (staden)",
        "back": "in the middle of the city, downtown",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e5ka (-er, \u00e5kte, \u00e5kt) runt",
        "back": "travel around",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "g\u00e5 p\u00e5 museum",
        "back": "go to a museum",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ABBA-museet",
        "back": "The ABBA Museum",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "promenera (-r, -de, -t) i ...",
        "back": "take a walk in ...",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "b\u00e5t (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "boat",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "b\u00e5ttur (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "boat tour",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "sk\u00e4rg\u00e5rd (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "archipelago",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "prinsesst\u00e5rta (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "Princess cake",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "designprylar",
        "back": "design stuff",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "Moderna museet",
        "back": "Museum of Modern Art",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "Fotografiska",
        "back": "Fotografiska Museum",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "dansmusik (-en)",
        "back": "dance music",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "Djurg\u00e5rden",
        "back": "Djurg\u00e5rden (district in Stockholm)",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00f6ttbulle (k\u00f6ttbullar, k\u00f6ttbullarna)",
        "back": "meatball",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "potatismos (-et)",
        "back": "mashed potatoes",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "sylt (-en)",
        "back": "jam, preserves",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "lingonsylt (-en)",
        "back": "lingonberry preserves",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "att g\u00f6ra-lista",
        "back": "to-do list",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "borde",
        "back": "should",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "information (-en)",
        "back": "information",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "t\u00e4nk dig att",
        "back": "imagine that",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "bes\u00f6ka (-er, -te, -t)",
        "back": "visit",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "presens perfekt",
        "back": "present perfect",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "supinum",
        "back": "supine",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "varannan",
        "back": "every other",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "beskriva (-er, beskrev, beskrivit)",
        "back": "describe",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "b\u00e4dda (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "make the bed",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "sl\u00e4cka (-er, -te, -t)",
        "back": "turn off",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "karaoke (-n)",
        "back": "karaoke",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "n\u00e5gon g\u00e5ng",
        "back": "some time",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "karaokebar (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "karaoke bar",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "Malm\u00f6",
        "back": "Malm\u00f6",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "Hur var den/det/de?",
        "back": "How was it / were they?",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "nerv\u00f6s (-t, -a)",
        "back": "nervous",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "supernerv\u00f6s",
        "back": "super nervous",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e5t (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "song",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "fr\u00e4mling (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "stranger",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "appl\u00e5d (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "applause",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "smaka (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "taste",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "i somras",
        "back": "last summer",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "varf\u00f6r inte",
        "back": "why not",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "j\u00e4ttekonstig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "really strange",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "salt (-a)",
        "back": "salty",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "hoppa fallsk\u00e4rm",
        "back": "go skydiving",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6r ... \u00e5r sedan",
        "back": "... years ago",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "i present",
        "back": "as a gift",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "hoppa (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "jump",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "r\u00e4dd (-a)",
        "back": "afraid",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "modig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "brave",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "dansa (-r, -ade, -t) tango",
        "back": "dance tango",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ex (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "ex (boyfriend, girlfriend)",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "danskurs (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "dance course",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "Grattis!",
        "back": "Congratulations!",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "pseudol\u00e5n (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "pseudo-loan",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "uttryck (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "expression",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "finnas (finns, fanns, funnits)",
        "back": "exist, be present",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "tidpunkt (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "point in time",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "tidsperiod (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "period",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "specifik (-t, -a)",
        "back": "specific",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "adverb (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "adverb",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e5ka vattenskidor",
        "back": "water skiing",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "rida (-er, red, ridit)",
        "back": "ride",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00e5la graffiti",
        "back": "paint graffiti",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "springa maraton",
        "back": "run a marathon",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "segla (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "sail",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "helikopter (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "helicopter",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "t\u00e4lta (-r, -ade, -t)",
        "back": "go camping (in a tent)",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "vinterbada (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "ice swimming",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00e4lsning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "greeting",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "skina (-er, sken, skinit)",
        "back": "shine",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "regna (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "rain",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "hela dagen",
        "back": "all day",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "augusti",
        "back": "August",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "starta (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "start",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "destination (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "destination",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rra veckan",
        "back": "last week",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ordningstal (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "ordinal numbers",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "sj\u00e4tte",
        "back": "sixth",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "sjunde",
        "back": "seventh",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e5ttonde",
        "back": "eighth",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "nionde",
        "back": "ninth",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "tionde",
        "back": "tenth",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "elfte",
        "back": "eleventh",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "tolfte",
        "back": "twelfth",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "trettonde",
        "back": "thirteenth",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "fjortonde",
        "back": "fourteenth",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "femtonde",
        "back": "fifteenth",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "sextonde",
        "back": "sixteenth",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "sjuttonde",
        "back": "seventeenth",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "artonde",
        "back": "eighteenth",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "nittonde",
        "back": "nineteenth",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "tjugonde",
        "back": "twentieth",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "tjugof\u00f6rsta",
        "back": "twenty-first",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "tjugoandra",
        "back": "twenty-second",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "trettionde",
        "back": "thirtieth",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "trettiof\u00f6rsta",
        "back": "thirty-first",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "januari",
        "back": "January",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "februari",
        "back": "February",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "mars",
        "back": "March",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "april",
        "back": "April",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "maj",
        "back": "May",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "juni",
        "back": "June",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "juli",
        "back": "July",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "aug",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter8"
    },
    {
        "front": "transport (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "transport",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "app (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "app",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "checka (-r, -de, -t) in",
        "back": "check in",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "flyg (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "flight",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "flygplats (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "airport",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00e4rja (-n, f\u00e4rjor, f\u00e4rjorna)",
        "back": "ferry",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00e4rjeterminal (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "ferry terminal",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00e5llplats (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "bus stop",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "restaurangvagn (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "restaurant carriage, dining car",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00e4kerhetskontroll (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "security check",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "sp\u00e5r (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "rail",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "t\u00e5g (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "train",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "vagn (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "carriage",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "N\u00e4r g\u00e5r t\u00e5get?",
        "back": "When does the train leave? / When is the train scheduled?",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Centralen",
        "back": "the Central Station",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "byta buss",
        "back": "change buses, transfer buses",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "tv\u00e5a buss",
        "back": "number 2 bus",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "fyra buss",
        "back": "number 4 bus",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e5tta",
        "back": "eight",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ladda (-r, -de, -t) ner",
        "back": "download",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "N\u00e4r g\u00e5r flyget?",
        "back": "When does the flight depart? / When is the flight scheduled?",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e4mna (-r, -de, -t) in",
        "back": "submit, hand in",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ta (-r, tog, tagit) l\u00e5ng tid",
        "back": "take a long time",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "koppla (-r, -de, -t) av",
        "back": "relax",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "gate (-n, -r, -rna)",
        "back": "gate",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "hemifr\u00e5n",
        "back": "from home",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "tidig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "early",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Tjoho!",
        "back": "Woohoo! / Yay!",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Helsingfors",
        "back": "Helsinki",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "fot (-en, f\u00f6tter, f\u00f6tterna)",
        "back": "foot",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "fordon (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "vehicle",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "tidtabell (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "timetable, schedule",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "rutt (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "route",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "informell (-t, -a)",
        "back": "informal",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "det \u00e4r ganska l\u00e5ngt",
        "back": "it\u2019s quite far",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "komma (-er, kom, kommit) in till/p\u00e5",
        "back": "arrive at",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "station (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "station",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "n\u00e4sta",
        "back": "next",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rsenad (-t, -e)",
        "back": "delayed",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "anslutningsbuss (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "connecting bus",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4nta (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "wait",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "flygbuss (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "airport bus",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Arlanda",
        "back": "Arlanda (international airport near Stockholm)",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "framme",
        "back": "arrived",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "terminal (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "terminal",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "inst\u00e4lld (-t, -a)",
        "back": "canceled",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "kanal (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "canal",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "klass (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "class",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e5ning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "floor",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "g\u00e5 i tv\u00e5an",
        "back": "be in second grade",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "sjua",
        "back": "seventh grade",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "nia",
        "back": "ninth grade",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "hiss (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "elevator, lift",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "torg (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "square",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "partikelverb (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "phrasal verb",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "partikel (-n, -lar, -larna)",
        "back": "particle",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "obetonad (-t, -e)",
        "back": "unstressed",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "betonad (-t, -de)",
        "back": "emphasized",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "verbpartikel",
        "back": "verb particle",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "komma (-er, kom, kommit) ih\u00e5g",
        "back": "remember",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Krya p\u00e5 dig!",
        "back": "Get well!",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "g\u00e5 (-r, gick, g\u00e5tt) av",
        "back": "get off",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "jul (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "Christmas",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "glass (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "ice cream",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "tunnelbana (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "subway, metro",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "bilresa (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "car trip",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "hotell (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "hotel",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "cykla (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "bike",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "pendelt\u00e5g (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "commuter train",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Hur kommer vi till ...?",
        "back": "How do we get to ...?",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "bageri (-et, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "bakery",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "skoaff\u00e4r (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "shoe store",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "bokhandel (-n, -lar, -larna)",
        "back": "bookstore",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "yogastudio (-n, -r, -rna)",
        "back": "yoga studio",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "sushirestaurang (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "sushi restaurant",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "optiker (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "optician",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "kl\u00e4dbutik (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "clothing store",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "korvkiosk (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "hot dog stand",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "elektronikaff\u00e4r (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "electronics store",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "kiosk (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "kiosk",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "kyrka (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "church",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "blomsterhandel (-n, -lar, -larna)",
        "back": "flower shop",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "preposition (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "preposition",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "korsning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "intersection, crossroads",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "mittemot",
        "back": "opposite",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "mellan ... och",
        "back": "between ... and",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4nster sida",
        "back": "on the left-hand side",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "trafikljus (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "traffic light",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e4ngs",
        "back": "along",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e5 (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "river",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6verg\u00e5ngsst\u00e4lle (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "crosswalk",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "g\u00e5 (-r, gick, g\u00e5tt) \u00f6ver gatan",
        "back": "cross the street",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "rondell (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "roundabout",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "bussh\u00e5llplats (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "bus stop",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "resa (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "trip",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "vandra (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "hike",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "fj\u00e4ll (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "mountain",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "n\u00e4rmare",
        "back": "closer",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "kolla (-r, -de, -t) upp",
        "back": "look up",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4stkust (-en)",
        "back": "west coast",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "strand (-en, str\u00e4nder, str\u00e4nderna)",
        "back": "beach",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Sk\u00e5ne",
        "back": "Sk\u00e5ne (southern Sweden)",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Siljan",
        "back": "Siljan Lake",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Dalarna",
        "back": "Dalarna (region in central Sweden)",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "festa (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "party",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Ume\u00e5",
        "back": "Ume\u00e5",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "G\u00f6teborg",
        "back": "Gothenburg",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "om 10 dagar",
        "back": "in 10 days",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "en dryg vecka",
        "back": "a little over a week",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "i s\u00e5 fall",
        "back": "in that case",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "guide (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "guide",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "nyhet (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "news",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "kontakt (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "contact",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "storstad (-en, storst\u00e4der, storst\u00e4derna)",
        "back": "big city",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "sj\u00f6 (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "lake",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ta (-r, tog, tagit) ett dopp",
        "back": "take a dip, have a swim",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "bad (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "swimming spot",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "V\u00e4nern",
        "back": "V\u00e4nern (largest lake in Sweden)",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "V\u00e4ttern",
        "back": "V\u00e4ttern (second largest lake in Sweden)",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Halland",
        "back": "Halland (region in southwestern Sweden)",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6 (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "island",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00d6land",
        "back": "\u00d6land (island in the Baltic Sea)",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "norra",
        "back": "northern",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "utanf\u00f6r",
        "back": "outside",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Lule\u00e5",
        "back": "Lule\u00e5",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "sand (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "sand",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "t\u00e5 (-n, -r, -rna)",
        "back": "toe",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "klippa (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "rock",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Bohusl\u00e4n",
        "back": "Bohusl\u00e4n (region in southwestern Sweden)",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Blekinge",
        "back": "Blekinge (region in southern Sweden)",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "puls (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "pulse",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "mysig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "cozy",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "sm\u00e5stad (-en, sm\u00e5st\u00e4der, sm\u00e5st\u00e4derna)",
        "back": "small town",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "stadssafari (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "city safari",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "kallbadhus (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "cold bath facility",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "snabb (-t, -a)",
        "back": "quick",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "enkel (-t, enkla)",
        "back": "simple",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "K\u00f6penhamn",
        "back": "Copenhagen",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "huvudstad (-en, huvudst\u00e4der, huvudst\u00e4derna)",
        "back": "capital city",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00e4rsk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "fresh",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "r\u00e4ka (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "shrimp",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "n\u00f6jespark (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "amusement park",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Avenyn",
        "back": "Avenyn (street in Gothenburg)",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "nattklubb (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "nightclub",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Drottninggatan",
        "back": "Drottninggatan (street in Stockholm)",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Stureplan",
        "back": "Stureplan (square in Stockholm)",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Sk\u00e5negatan",
        "back": "Sk\u00e5negatan (street in Stockholm)",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Skeppsholmen",
        "back": "Skeppsholmen (island in Stockholm)",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ringmur (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "city wall, ring wall",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "medeltid (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "Middle Ages",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "kyrkby (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "church village",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "utsikt (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "view",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "frisk luft",
        "back": "fresh air",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Lappland",
        "back": "Lapland",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "vandringsled (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "hiking trail",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "fj\u00e4llstation (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "mountain station",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "dagstur (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "day trip",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "nyb\u00f6rjare (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "beginner",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "H\u00f6ga kusten",
        "back": "High Coast",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "tunnelbanestation (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "subway station",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "bildgoogla (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "image search",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "p\u00e5 kartan",
        "back": "on the map",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "generell (-t, -a)",
        "back": "general",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "tidspreposition (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "preposition of time",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "rast (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "break",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "landskap (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "landscape",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "region (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "region",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "vandrarhem (-met, \u2013, -men)",
        "back": "hostel",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "stavning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "spelling",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "forskning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "research",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "skinka (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "ham",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "meddelande (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "message",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "skapa (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "create",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "tr\u00e5d (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "thread",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "rundresa (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "circular trip",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e4lskling (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "darling",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "tillbaka",
        "back": "back",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Sj\u00e4lvklart!",
        "back": "Of course!",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "Kram!",
        "back": "Hugs!",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "leka (-er, -te, -t)",
        "back": "play",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "granne (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "neighbor",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "puss (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "kiss",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "flyga (-er, fl\u00f6g, flugit)",
        "back": "fly",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "vattna (-r, -de, -t) blommor",
        "back": "water the flowers",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "underlag (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "reference",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "vart",
        "back": "where to",
        "chapter": "Chapter9"
    },
    {
        "front": "veta (vet, visste, vetat)",
        "back": "know",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "platt (-a)",
        "back": "flat",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "kustlinje (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "coastline",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "yta (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "surface",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "t\u00e4tbefolkad (-t, -e)",
        "back": "densely populated",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ursprungsfolk (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "indigenous people",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "gr\u00e4ns (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "border",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "jordbruk (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "agriculture",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "fattig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "poor",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "arbetskraft (-en)",
        "back": "manpower",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e4ndra (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "change",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "flykting (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "refugee",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00f6ka (-er, -te, -t) asyl",
        "back": "apply for asylum",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "asyl (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "asylum",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "j\u00e4rn (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "iron",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "st\u00e5l (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "steel",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "skandinavisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Scandinavian",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "polcirkel (-n, polcirklar, polcirklarna)",
        "back": "Arctic Circle",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "genom",
        "back": "through",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00f6dra",
        "back": "southern",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "jordbruksmark (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "farmland",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "procent (-en)",
        "back": "percent",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "skogsmark (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "woodland",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00d6stersj\u00f6n",
        "back": "Baltic Sea",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "blandning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "mixture",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00f6tvatten (-net, \u2013, -nen)",
        "back": "freshwater",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "saltvatten (-net, \u2013, -nen)",
        "back": "saltwater",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "br\u00e4ckt vatten",
        "back": "brackish water",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00e4nniska (-n, m\u00e4nniskor, m\u00e4nniskorna)",
        "back": "human, person",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "kommunal (-t, -a)",
        "back": "municipal",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "glesbefolkad (-t, -e)",
        "back": "sparsely populated",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "inv\u00e5nare (-n, \u2013, inv\u00e5narna)",
        "back": "resident, population",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "kvadratkilometer (-n, \u2013, kvadratkilometrarna)",
        "back": "square kilometer",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "same (-n, -r, -rna)",
        "back": "Sami person",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "samiska",
        "back": "Sami / Saami",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "parlament (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "parliament",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "Tornedalen",
        "back": "Tornedalen (region along the Swedish\u2013Finnish border)",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "tornedaling (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "Tornedalian",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "me\u00e4nkieli",
        "back": "Me\u00e4nkieli (Finnish dialect in northern Sweden)",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "huvudspr\u00e5k (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "main language",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "officiell (-t, -a)",
        "back": "official",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "internationell (-t, -a)",
        "back": "international",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "sammanhang (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "context",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "jiddisch",
        "back": "Yiddish",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "romska",
        "back": "Romani",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "nationell (-t, -a)",
        "back": "national",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "minoritetsspr\u00e5k (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "minority language",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rr i tiden",
        "back": "the olden days",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "jordbruksland (-et, jordbruksl\u00e4nder, jordbruksl\u00e4nderna)",
        "back": "farmland country",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "svensk (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "Swede",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "emigrera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "emigrate",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "mest",
        "back": "mostly",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "Nordamerika",
        "back": "North America",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "industri (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "industry",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4xa (-er, -te, -t)",
        "back": "grow",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "d\u00e4rf\u00f6r",
        "back": "therefore",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "nordisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Nordic",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "Sydeuropa",
        "back": "Southern Europe",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "1960-talet",
        "back": "the 1960s",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "arbeta (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "work",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "inom",
        "back": "within",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00e4mre",
        "back": "worse",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "politik (-en)",
        "back": "politics",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "invandring (-en)",
        "back": "immigration",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "samtidig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "at the same time",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "Latinamerika",
        "back": "Latin America",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "Mellan\u00f6stern",
        "back": "Middle East",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "forna Jugoslavien",
        "back": "former Yugoslavia",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "EU-medborgare (-n, \u2013, EU-medborgarna)",
        "back": "EU citizen",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "femtedel (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "a fifth",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00f6gutbildad (-t, -e)",
        "back": "highly educated",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "it-specialist (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "IT specialist",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00e4songsarbetare (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "seasonal worker",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "plocka (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "pick",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "export (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "export",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "exportera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "export",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "tr\u00e4 (-et)",
        "back": "wood",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "pappersmassa (-n, pappersmassor, pappersmassorna)",
        "back": "wood pulp",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e4ven",
        "back": "even",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "lastbil (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "truck",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e4kemedel (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "medicine",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "maskin (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "machine",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "produkt (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "product",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "tj\u00e4nst (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "service",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "telekom (-en)",
        "back": "telecommunications",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "mobiltelefoni (-n)",
        "back": "mobile technology",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "musikindustri (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "music industry",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "artist (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "artist",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "utomlands",
        "back": "abroad",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e5tskrivare (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "songwriter",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "producent (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "producer",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "sektor (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "sector",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "databranschen (-en)",
        "back": "the IT industry",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "mobilspelbranschen (-en)",
        "back": "the mobile gaming industry",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "spel (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "game",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "utveckla (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "develop",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "spelf\u00f6retag (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "gaming company",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "minoritet (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "minority",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "sverigefinne (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "Sweden Finn",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "jude (-n, judar, judarna)",
        "back": "Jew",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "rom (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "Roma / Romani",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "finska",
        "back": "Finnish",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "helt",
        "back": "completely",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "politiker (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "politician",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "diplomat (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "diplomat",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "vetenskapsman (-nen, vetenskapsm\u00e4n, vetenskapsm\u00e4nnen)",
        "back": "scientist",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "regiss\u00f6r (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "director",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "kokboksf\u00f6rfattare (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "cookbook author",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "helgon (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "saint",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "operas\u00e5ngare (-n, \u2013, operas\u00e5ngarna)",
        "back": "opera singer",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "fotbollsspelare (-n, \u2013, fotbollsspelarna)",
        "back": "football (soccer) player",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "drottning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "queen",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "det mesta",
        "back": "most",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "normal (-t, -a)",
        "back": "normal",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "studenttidning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "student paper",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "utbytesstudent (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "exchange student",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "svar (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "answer",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "kebabpizza (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "kebab pizza",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "fl\u00e4skfil\u00e9 (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "pork tenderloin",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "praktisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "practical",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "tobak (-en)",
        "back": "tobacco",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "under",
        "back": "under",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e4pp (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "lip",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "smak (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "taste, flavor",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "eukalyptus (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "eucalyptus",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e4cklig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "disgusting",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "Haparanda",
        "back": "Haparanda",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "makaroner (-na)",
        "back": "macaroni",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "dra (-r, drog, dragit) in luft",
        "back": "inhale, breathe in",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "astma (-n)",
        "back": "asthma",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e5r (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "spring",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "utomhus",
        "back": "outside",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e4nd\u00e5",
        "back": "anyway",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "grilla (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "barbecue",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ute",
        "back": "outside",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "i rad",
        "back": "in a row",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "gullig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "cute",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "snabbfakta",
        "back": "quick facts",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "konstitutionell monarki",
        "back": "constitutional monarchy",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "svensk krona (SEK)",
        "back": "Swedish krona",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "Kebnekaise",
        "back": "Kebnekaise (Sweden\u2019s highest peak)",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e4lv (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "river",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "statskick (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "system of government",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "befolkning (-en)",
        "back": "population",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "befolkningst\u00e4thet (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "population density",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "vattendrag (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "watercourse",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "berg (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "mountain",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "valuta (-n, valutor, valutorna)",
        "back": "currency",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "landskod (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "country code",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "landsnummer (landsnumret, \u2013, landsnumren)",
        "back": "country calling code",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rnamn (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "first name, given name",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "tilltalsnamn (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "first name",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "separat (-a)",
        "back": "separate",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "kvinnonamn (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "woman\u2019s name",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "mansnamn (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "man\u2019s name",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "10 i topp",
        "back": "Top 10",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4lja (-er, valde, valt)",
        "back": "choose",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "nyckelord (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "keywords",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "geografi (-n)",
        "back": "geography",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "religion (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "religion",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6stra",
        "back": "eastern",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4stra",
        "back": "western",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "central (-t, -a)",
        "back": "central",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "gr\u00e4nsa (-r, -de, -t) till",
        "back": "border on",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6ken (\u00f6knen, \u00f6knar, \u00f6knarna)",
        "back": "desert",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "muslim (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "Muslim",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "hindu (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "Hindu",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "kristen (kristna)",
        "back": "Christian",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "protestant (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "Protestant",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ortodoxt kristna",
        "back": "Orthodox Christians",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "katolik (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "Catholic",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "odla (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "cultivate, grow",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "producera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "produce",
        "chapter": "Chapter10"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4nskap (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "friendship",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "nyfiken (-t, -a)",
        "back": "curious",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "vuxen (vuxet, vuxna)",
        "back": "adult",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "fritidsaktivitet (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "leisure activity",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e4ra k\u00e4nna (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "get to know",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6ppen f\u00f6rskola",
        "back": "drop-in preschool",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "bebis (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "baby",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "gratis",
        "back": "for free",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6r\u00e4ldraledig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "on parental leave",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "spontan (-t, -a)",
        "back": "spontaneous",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "lojal (-t, -a)",
        "back": "loyal",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "kasse (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "bag",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "hj\u00e4lpsam (-t, -ma)",
        "back": "helpful",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "t\u00e5lamod (-et)",
        "back": "patience",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "gn\u00e4lla (-er, -de, -t)",
        "back": "complain",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "dagens",
        "back": "today\u2019s",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ungdom (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "youth",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "skratta (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "laugh",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "klok (-t, -a)",
        "back": "wise",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "mentor (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "mentor",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "glasst\u00e4lle (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "ice cream shop",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "samh\u00e4lle (-t, -en, -ena)",
        "back": "society",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "skejta (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "skate",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "skejtare (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "skater",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "skejtpark (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "skatepark",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "pirrig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "excited",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "duktig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "good, capable",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "peppa (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "encourage, hype up",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "skejtklipp (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "skate clip",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "vegansk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "vegan",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "grej (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "thing",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ovanlig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "unusual",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6resl\u00e5 (-r, f\u00f6rslog, f\u00f6reslagit)",
        "back": "suggest",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00f6r (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "choir",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "golf (-en)",
        "back": "golf",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "konstutst\u00e4llning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "art exhibition",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "spr\u00e5kkurs (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "language course",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "dejta (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "date",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "bjuda (-er, bj\u00f6d, bjudit)",
        "back": "invite",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "krog (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "bar, restaurant",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "tjejkompis (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "female friend",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "inte l\u00e4ngre",
        "back": "no longer",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "hundpromenad (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "dog walk",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "dam (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "lady",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "skolflicka (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "schoolgirl",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rskolebarn (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "preschool child",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "snygging (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "good-looking person",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "tipsa (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "tip",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "rekommendera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "recommend",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "metod (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "method",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "utst\u00e4llning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "exhibition",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "tavla (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "painting",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "pr\u00f6va (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "try, test",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "n\u00e4tdejting (-en)",
        "back": "online dating",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "profil (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "profile",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "dejtingapp (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "dating app",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "mess (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "text message",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "barnfri (-tt, -a)",
        "back": "child-free",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "sportig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "athletic",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00f6pning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "running",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "motorsport (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "motorsport",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "fet (-t, -a)",
        "back": "cool",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "motorcykel (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "motorcycle",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "Rom",
        "back": "Rome",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "radera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "delete",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "inte heller",
        "back": "neither",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "sportbar (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "sports bar",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "mellan jobb",
        "back": "between jobs",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "trist (-, -a)",
        "back": "boring",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "Hall\u00e5 d\u00e4r!",
        "back": "Hello there!",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "fr\u00e5nskild (-t, -a)",
        "back": "divorced",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "st\u00e4da (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "clean up",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "tv\u00e4tta (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "do the laundry",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "stryka (-er, str\u00f6k, strukit)",
        "back": "iron",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "t\u00e5la (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "tolerate",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "nick (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "nickname",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "sporthatare (-n, \u2013, -sporthatarna)",
        "back": "sports hater",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "mikro (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "microwave",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "i n\u00e4rheten",
        "back": "nearby",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "g\u00e5rd (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "farm",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "hj\u00e4rtlig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "heartfelt",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "frys (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "freezer",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "pirog (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "pasty",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "redo",
        "back": "ready",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "chans (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "chance, opportunity",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ta chansen (-r, tog, tagit)",
        "back": "take the chance",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "Tjenixen!",
        "back": "Hi there! / Hey!",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "uteliv (-et)",
        "back": "nightlife",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "annars",
        "back": "otherwise",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00f6rkort (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "driver\u2019s license",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "sitta (-er, satt, suttit) bak",
        "back": "sit in the back",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "snart",
        "back": "soon",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ocks\u00e5",
        "back": "also, too",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "Mars",
        "back": "Mars",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ljuga (-er, lj\u00f6g, ljugit)",
        "back": "lie",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ingenting",
        "back": "nothing",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "arbetsl\u00f6s (-a)",
        "back": "unemployed",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "bostadsl\u00f6s (-a)",
        "back": "homeless",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "huslig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "domestic",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ironisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "ironic",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ointressant (-a)",
        "back": "uninteresting",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "t\u00f6ntig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "dorky, uncool",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e4ventyrlig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "adventurous",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "verka (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "seem",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "fritid (-en)",
        "back": "free time",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "repetera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "repeat",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "tabell (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "table",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "lukta (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "smell",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "lyssnare (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "listener",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e4sare (-n, \u2013, l\u00e4sarna)",
        "back": "reader",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "genitiv (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "genitive",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "digital (-t, -a)",
        "back": "digital",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "tangentbord (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "keyboard",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "papperskorg (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "wastepaper basket",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "sladd (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "cord",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "kabel (-n, kablar, kablarna)",
        "back": "cable",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "kursiv stil (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "italics",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "spara (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "save",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "skriva ut (-er, skrev, skrivit)",
        "back": "print",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "snabel-a (-et, -n, -na)",
        "back": "@ symbol",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "mapp (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "folder",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "fet stil",
        "back": "bold",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "bindestreck (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "hyphen",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e5ngra (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "undo",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "hashtagg / fyrkant",
        "back": "hashtag",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "bifoga (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "attach",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "mus (-en)",
        "back": "mouse",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "webbkamera (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "webcam",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "punkt (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "period, full stop",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "understreck (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "underline",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "sk\u00e4rm (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "screen",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6ppna (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "open",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "utropstecken (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "exclamation point",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "fr\u00e5getecken (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "question mark",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "snedstreck (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "slash",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "typsnitt (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "font",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00f6ka (-r, -te, -t)",
        "back": "search",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "klistra in (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "paste",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e4nk (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "link",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "fungera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "work",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "fylla p\u00e5 (-er, -de, -t)",
        "back": "refill",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "godk\u00e4nna (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "approve",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "hackad (-t, -a)",
        "back": "hacked",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "klicka (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "click",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ansluta (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "connect",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "koppla (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "connect",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "logga in (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "log in",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00f6senord (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "password",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "muta (-er, -de, -t)",
        "back": "mute",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "starta om (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "restart",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "stoppa in (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "put in",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00e4tta p\u00e5 (-er, satte, satt)",
        "back": "turn on",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "funka (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "work",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "titta (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "look",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "Nu g\u00e5r det.",
        "back": "Now it\u2019s working.",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ikon (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "icon",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "trasig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "broken",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00e4nda (-er, -de, -t)",
        "back": "happen",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "Pang!",
        "back": "Bang!",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "Det sa bara pang!",
        "back": "It just went bang!",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "usb-ing\u00e5ng (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "USB port",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "dokument (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "document",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "skrivare (-n, \u2013, skrivarna)",
        "back": "printer",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "gl\u00f6mma (gl\u00f6mmer, gl\u00f6mde, gl\u00f6mt)",
        "back": "forget",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "inbjudan (-en, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "invitation",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "mikrofon (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "microphone",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "st\u00e4nga av (-er, -de, -t)",
        "back": "turn off",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "e-postadress (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "email address",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ordbetoning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "word stress",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "stavelse (-n, -er, -rna)",
        "back": "syllable",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "matematik (-en)",
        "back": "mathematics",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "profiltext (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "bio",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "dejtingsida (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "dating site",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "seri\u00f6s (-t, -a)",
        "back": "serious",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ambiti\u00f6s (-t, -a)",
        "back": "ambitious",
        "chapter": "Chapter11"
    },
    {
        "front": "favoritmat (-en, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "favorite food",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "matr\u00e4tt (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "dish",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "jordgubbskr\u00e4m (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "strawberry pur\u00e9e",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00e5ldolme (-n, k\u00e5ldolmar, k\u00e5ldolmarna)",
        "back": "cabbage roll",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "pyttipanna (-n)",
        "back": "Swedish hash",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "stekt \u00e4gg",
        "back": "fried egg",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "r\u00f6dbeta (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "beetroot",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "raggmunk (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "potato pancake",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "fl\u00e4sk (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "pork",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "ripa (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "grouse",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "gr\u00e4dds\u00e5s (-en, \u2013, -er)",
        "back": "gravy",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "r\u00f6nnb\u00e4rsgel\u00e9 (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "rowanberry jelly",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "spagetti",
        "back": "spaghetti",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "varmkorv (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "hot dog",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e4lgstek (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "moose steak",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "klyftpotatis (-en, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "potato wedges",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "svartvinb\u00e4rsgel\u00e9 (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "blackcurrant jelly",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rtjust i",
        "back": "fond of, keen on",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "biff med l\u00f6k",
        "back": "steak with onions",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "ris (-et)",
        "back": "rice",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "sm\u00e5kakor (-na)",
        "back": "small cookies, biscuits",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "husmanskost (-en)",
        "back": "traditional Swedish home cooking",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "traditionell (-t, -a)",
        "back": "traditional",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "titta efter (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "look for",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "r\u00e4ttvisem\u00e4rkt (-a)",
        "back": "fair trade",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "bondg\u00e5rd (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "farm",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "n\u00e4rproducerad (-t, -a)",
        "back": "locally produced",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "blad (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "leaf",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "urd\u00e5lig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "really bad, terrible",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "matlagning (-en)",
        "back": "cooking",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00e4mtmat (-en)",
        "back": "takeout food",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "thai",
        "back": "thai",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "sushi (-n)",
        "back": "sushi",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "falafel",
        "back": "falafel",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "klimatsmart (-a)",
        "back": "environmentally friendly",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "sparris (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "asparagus",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "tofu (-n)",
        "back": "tofu",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "korv (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "sausage, hot dog",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "mj\u00f6lkprodukt (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "dairy product",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "laktosintolerant (-a)",
        "back": "lactose intolerant",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "vete (-t)",
        "back": "wheat",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "glutenallergi (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "gluten allergy",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "svamp (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "mushroom",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "torka (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "dry",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "koka (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "boil",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00e4rdigr\u00e4tt (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "ready-made meal",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "pulvermos (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "instant mashed potatoes",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "stor stark",
        "back": "large draft beer",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "bisats (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "subordinate clause",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "subjunktion (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "subordinating conjunction",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "jordgubbst\u00e5rta (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "strawberry cake",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "indisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Indian",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "norsk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Norwegian",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "colombiansk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Colombian",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "algerisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Algerian",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "nationalitet (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "nationality",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "afghansk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Afghan",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "australiensisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Australian",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "brasiliansk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Brazilian",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "brittisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "British",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "eritreansk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Eritrean",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "etiopisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Ethiopian",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "finsk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Finnish",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "fransk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "French",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "grekisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Greek",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "indonesisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Indonesian",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "irakisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Iraqi",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "iransk/persisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Iranian, Persian",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "italiensk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Italian",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "japansk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Japanese",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "kenyansk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Kenyan",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "kinesisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Chinese",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "koreansk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Korean",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "kubansk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Cuban",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "libanesisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Lebanese",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "marockansk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Moroccan",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "mexikansk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Mexican",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "nyzeel\u00e4ndsk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "New Zealander",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "pakistansk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Pakistani",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "polsk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Polish",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "rysk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Russian",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "sydafrikansk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "South African",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "syrisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Syrian",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "thail\u00e4ndsk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Thai",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "tunisisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Tunisian",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "turkisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Turkish",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "tysk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "German",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "ukrainsk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Ukrainian",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "ungersk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Hungarian",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6sterrikisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "Austrian",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "anteckna (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "make notes",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "blodpudding (-en)",
        "back": "blood pudding",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "r\u00e5vara (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "raw ingredient",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "rotfrukt (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "root vegetable",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4xt (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "plant",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "midsommar (-en, midsomrar, midsomrarna)",
        "back": "midsummer",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00e4desslag (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "cereal grain",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "invandrare (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "immigrant",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "introducera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "introduce",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "pizzasallad (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "pizza salad",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00e5lsallad (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "cabbage salad",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "Kroatien",
        "back": "Croatia",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "nord\u00f6stra",
        "back": "northeastern",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "kebab (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "kebab",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "vardagsmat (-en)",
        "back": "everyday food",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "ostkust (-en)",
        "back": "east coast",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "inlagd (inlagt, -a)",
        "back": "pickled",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e4ttika (-n)",
        "back": "Swedish vinegar",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "kryddning (-en, \u2013, -ar)",
        "back": "seasoning",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "senapssill (-en)",
        "back": "herring in mustard sauce",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00f6ksill (-en)",
        "back": "onion-marinated herring",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "exempelvis",
        "back": "for example",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "wasabisill (-en)",
        "back": "wasabi-marinated herring",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "baconsill (-en)",
        "back": "bacon-flavored herring",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "str\u00f6mming (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "Baltic herring",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "surstr\u00f6mming (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "fermented Baltic herring",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "syrad (-t, -e)",
        "back": "fermented",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "fermenterad (fermenterat, -e)",
        "back": "fermented",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "stark (-t, -a)",
        "back": "strong",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rr\u00e4n",
        "back": "until",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "br\u00e4nnvin (-et)",
        "back": "vodka, aquavit",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "bas (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "staple",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "dubbelt s\u00e5 mycket",
        "back": "twice as much",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00e4rskpotatis (-en, \u2013, -arna)",
        "back": "new potatoes",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "nykokt (-a)",
        "back": "freshly boiled",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "dill (-en)",
        "back": "dill",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "r\u00e5g (-en)",
        "back": "rye",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "klimat (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "climate",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "blanda (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "mix",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "r\u00e5gmj\u00f6l (-et)",
        "back": "rye flour",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "tunn (-t, -a)",
        "back": "thin",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "skafferi (-t, -r, -rna)",
        "back": "pantry",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "tunnbr\u00f6d",
        "back": "flatbread",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "korn",
        "back": "barley",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "meter (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "meter",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4ga (-er, -de, -t)",
        "back": "weigh",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "ton (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "pitch",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "ha tur (-r, hade, haft)",
        "back": "be lucky",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e4lgk\u00f6tt (-et)",
        "back": "moose meat",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "n\u00f6tk\u00f6tt (-et)",
        "back": "beef",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "lingon (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "lingonberry",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "vild (vilt, -a)",
        "back": "wild",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "saft (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "juice",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "r\u00e5r\u00f6rda lingon",
        "back": "raw-stirred lingonberries",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "kroppkakor",
        "back": "potato dumplings",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "fl\u00e4skpannkaka",
        "back": "pork pancake",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "jordgubbsfeber (-n)",
        "back": "strawberry fever",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "mogen (-et, -na)",
        "back": "ripe",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "importerad (-t, -de)",
        "back": "imported",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "midsommarhelg (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "Midsummer weekend",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "sj\u00e4lvplock (-et)",
        "back": "pick-your-own",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "kr\u00e4m (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "fruit pur\u00e9e",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e4gga (-er, lade, lagt)",
        "back": "put",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "gr\u00e4ddt\u00e5rta (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "whipped cream cake",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "naturell (-t, -a)",
        "back": "plain, natural",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "fett (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "fat",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "rad (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "line",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00e5",
        "back": "few",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "pannkaka (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "pancake",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "buff\u00e9 (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "buffet",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "lax (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "salmon",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "minipizza (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "mini pizza",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00e4tt (-a)",
        "back": "full",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "pralin (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "praline",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "g\u00e4st (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "guest",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "tv\u00e4rtom",
        "back": "the opposite",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "annorlunda",
        "back": "different",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "haj (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "shark",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00e4ker (-t, s\u00e4kra)",
        "back": "certain",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e5sikt (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "opinion",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4rdering (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "value",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "i vinter",
        "back": "this winter",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00f6rk choklad (-en)",
        "back": "dark chocolate",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "mj\u00f6lkchoklad (-en)",
        "back": "milk chocolate",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "st\u00e4nga (-er, -de, -t)",
        "back": "close",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "p\u00e5 v\u00e4g",
        "back": "on the way",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00e5 l\u00e4nge",
        "back": "for now",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "alkoholfri (-tt, -a)",
        "back": "non-alcoholic",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "ett glas r\u00f6tt",
        "back": "a glass of red wine",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "sorter",
        "back": "types, kinds",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "hemlagad (-t, -e)",
        "back": "homemade",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "tacka (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "thank",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "dessert (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "dessert",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "avec (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "after-dinner drink",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "efterr\u00e4tt (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "dessert",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "Kan vi f\u00e5 notan?",
        "back": "May we have the bill?",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "chokladbit (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "piece of chocolate",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "Ska vi dela rakt av?",
        "back": "Should we split it evenly?",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "dricksa (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "tip",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "hundring (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "a hundred (SEK)",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "vr\u00e5lhungrig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "starving",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "tillbeh\u00f6r (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "side dish",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "Mums.",
        "back": "Yum.",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "torka av (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "wipe off",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "smula (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "crumb",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "visst",
        "back": "sure, of course",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "herregud",
        "back": "oh my god",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "huvudr\u00e4tt (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "main course",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "gr\u00f6nsallad (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "green salad",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "j\u00e4ttesugen (-et, -na)",
        "back": "really craving",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e4gga dricks (-er, lade, lagt)",
        "back": "leave a tip",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "swisha (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "pay with Swish",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "tendens (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "tendency",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "till vardags",
        "back": "in everyday life",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "satsdel (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "part of a sentence",
        "chapter": "Chapter12"
    },
    {
        "front": "skolklass (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "class",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "planet (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "planet",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "astronaut (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "astronaut",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00e5nen (-en)",
        "back": "the moon",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "d\u00e4rifr\u00e5n",
        "back": "from there",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "rymden (-en)",
        "back": "space",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "rymdraket (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "space rocket",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "tr\u00e4dg\u00e5rdsm\u00e4stare (-n, \u2013, tr\u00e4dg\u00e5rdsm\u00e4starna)",
        "back": "gardener",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "kontor (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "office",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "stirra (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "stare",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "fotbollsproffs (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "football/soccer player",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "rappare (-n, \u2013, rapparna)",
        "back": "rapper",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "polisbil (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "police car",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "veterin\u00e4r (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "veterinarian",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "tandhygienist (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "dental hygienist",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "Det st\u00e4mmer.",
        "back": "That\u2019s right.",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "inne",
        "back": "inside",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "ute",
        "back": "outside",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "uppe",
        "back": "up there, above",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "nere",
        "back": "down there, below",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "framme",
        "back": "in an easily noticeable spot",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "borta",
        "back": "away",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "vart",
        "back": "where to",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "dit",
        "back": "there",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "hit",
        "back": "here",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "bort",
        "back": "away",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "d\u00e4rifr\u00e5n",
        "back": "from there",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00e4rifr\u00e5n",
        "back": "from here",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "inifr\u00e5n",
        "back": "from inside",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "utifr\u00e5n",
        "back": "from outside",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "uppifr\u00e5n",
        "back": "from above",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "nerifr\u00e5n",
        "back": "from below",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "framifr\u00e5n",
        "back": "from in front",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "bortifr\u00e5n",
        "back": "from over there",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "rymdfysiker (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "space physicist",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "institut (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "institute",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "rymdfysik (-en)",
        "back": "space physics",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "doktorera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "get a PhD",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "norrsken (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "northern lights / aurora borealis",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "forskningsprojekt (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "research project",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "skr\u00e4ckroman (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "horror novel",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "jobba (-r, -de, -t) \u00f6ver",
        "back": "work overtime",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "hush\u00e5llsarbete (-t, \u2013, -n)",
        "back": "household chores",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "skoter (-n, -rar, -rarna)",
        "back": "snowmobile",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "intensiv (-t, -a)",
        "back": "intense",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "stressig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "stressful",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rsova (-er, f\u00f6rsov, f\u00f6rsovit) sig",
        "back": "oversleep",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "ostfrall (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "cheese sandwich",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "presentera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "present",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "resultat (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "result",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "uppsats (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "essay, thesis",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "rymdbas (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "space base",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "amerikan (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "American",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "skynda (-r, -de, -t) sig",
        "back": "hurry",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "duka (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "set the table",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "norrl\u00e4ndsk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "from Norrland, Northern Swedish",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "vargtass",
        "back": "vargtass (traditional Swedish drink with lingonberry juice and vodka)",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4lkomstdrink (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "welcome drink",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "fj\u00e4llr\u00f6ding (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "Arctic char",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "mandelpotatis (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "almond potato",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "hjortronglass (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "cloudberry ice cream",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "lingonsaft (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "lingonberry juice",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6nster (f\u00f6nstret, \u2013, f\u00f6nstren)",
        "back": "window",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "magisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "magical",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rskoll\u00e4rare (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "preschool teacher",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "larm (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "alarm",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "golv (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "floor",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "saga (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "fairy tale",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "br\u00e5ka (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "fight, argue",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "lekpark (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "playground",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "sandl\u00e5da (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "sandbox",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "gunga (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "swing",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "konferens (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "conference",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "i f\u00f6rrg\u00e5r",
        "back": "the day before yesterday",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "aktuell (-t, -a)",
        "back": "relevant",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "Chile",
        "back": "Chile",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "grammatikprov (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "grammar test",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "snickare (-n, \u2013, snickarna)",
        "back": "carpenter",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "butikss\u00e4ljare",
        "back": "store clerk, shop assistant",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e4xhj\u00e4lpare",
        "back": "homework helper, tutor",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "siml\u00e4rare (-n, \u2013, siml\u00e4rarna)",
        "back": "swimming instructor",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "receptionist (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "receptionist",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "grafisk formgivare",
        "back": "graphic designer",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "bilmekaniker (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "car mechanic",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "bartender (-n, -tendrar, -na)",
        "back": "bartender",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00e4ndig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "dexterous, skillful",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "noggrann (-t, -a)",
        "back": "careful, meticulous",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "pedagogisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "pedagogical",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "kreativ (-t, -a)",
        "back": "creative",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "social (-t, -a)",
        "back": "social",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "serviceinriktad (-t, -e)",
        "back": "service-minded",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "bra med barn",
        "back": "good with children",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "teknisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "technical",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "omt\u00e4nksam (-t, -ma)",
        "back": "caring",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "konsthistoria (-n)",
        "back": "art history",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "maskiningenj\u00f6r (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "mechanical engineer",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "KTH = Kungliga Tekniska H\u00f6gskolan",
        "back": "Royal Institute of Technology",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "extrajobb (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "extra work, part-time job",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "idrottsl\u00e4rare (-n, \u2013, idrottsl\u00e4rarna)",
        "back": "physical education teacher",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00f6gstadiet (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "lower secondary school",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "milj\u00f6vetenskap (-en)",
        "back": "environmental science",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "sabbats\u00e5r (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "gap year",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "pyssla (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "do crafts",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "dammsuga (-er, damms\u00f6g, dammsugit)",
        "back": "vacuum clean",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "saffransrisotto (-n)",
        "back": "saffron risotto",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "arbetsdag (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "workday",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "arbetsuppgift (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "task",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "diska (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "wash the dishes",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "vattengympa (-n)",
        "back": "water aerobics",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "hotellfrukost (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "hotel breakfast",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "vara (-r, var, varit) ledig",
        "back": "be off work, have free time",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "organisation (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "organization",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "personal (-en)",
        "back": "staff",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "spontanans\u00f6kan (-en, -ningar, -ningarna)",
        "back": "unsolicited application",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "UX-designer (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "UX designer",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "bransch (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "industry",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "byr\u00e5 (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "agency",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "kund (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "customer",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "undra (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "wonder",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "medarbetare (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "employee",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "projekt (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "project",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4nliga h\u00e4lsningar",
        "back": "best regards",
        "chapter": "Chapter13"
    },
    {
        "front": "fast jobb",
        "back": "permanent position",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "betald semester",
        "back": "paid vacation",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rs\u00e4kringsbolag (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "insurance company",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6ljande",
        "back": "the following",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "b\u00e5tsemester (-n, -rar, -rarna)",
        "back": "boating holiday",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "campingsemester (-n, -rar, -rarna)",
        "back": "camping holiday",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "cykelsemester (-n, -rar, -rarna)",
        "back": "cycling holiday",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "vandringssemester (-n, -rar, -rarna)",
        "back": "hiking holiday",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "motorcykelsemester (-n, -rar, -rarna)",
        "back": "motorcycling holiday",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "sommarstuga (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "summer cottage, holiday home",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "hyra (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "rent",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "stuga (-n, stugor, stugorna)",
        "back": "cottage",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "statistik (-en)",
        "back": "statistics",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e4ngst ner",
        "back": "at the bottom",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "gissa (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "guess",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rv\u00e5nad (-t, -de)",
        "back": "surprised",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "n\u00e5got helt annat",
        "back": "something completely different",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "fritidshus (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "holiday home",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "hav (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "sea",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "semesterdr\u00f6m (-men, -mar, -marna)",
        "back": "holiday dream",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e5ka (-er, -te, -t) b\u00e5t",
        "back": "go boating",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "barfota",
        "back": "barefoot",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "gr\u00e4s (-et)",
        "back": "grass",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "frihet (-en)",
        "back": "freedom",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e4n",
        "back": "than",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "spela (-r, -de, -t) kort",
        "back": "play cards",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "lycklig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "happy",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "dr\u00f6m (-men, -mar, -marna)",
        "back": "dream",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00e5la (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "paint",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "renovera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "renovate",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "klippa (-er, -te, -t) gr\u00e4s",
        "back": "cut the grass, mow the lawn",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "hugga (-er, h\u00f6gg, huggit)",
        "back": "chop",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "ved (-en)",
        "back": "wood",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "sola (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "sunbathe",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00f6jlighet (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "possibility",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "lantst\u00e4lle (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "country house",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "landst\u00e4lle (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "country house",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "sommarhus (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "summer house",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "torp (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "croft",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "ropa (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "shout",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "lakan (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "bedsheets",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "direkt tal",
        "back": "direct speech",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "indirekt tal",
        "back": "indirect speech",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "sats (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "clause",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "bisatsinledare (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "subordinate conjunction",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "ifall",
        "back": "in case, if",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "hjortron (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "cloudberry",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "fr\u00e5geordsfr\u00e5ga (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "wh-question",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "bilf\u00e4rja (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "car ferry",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00e5s (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "seagull",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "skrika (-er, skrek, skrikit)",
        "back": "scream",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00e4rjel\u00e4ge (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "ferry landing",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "grusv\u00e4g (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "gravel road",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "tr\u00e4d (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "tree",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "glittra (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "glitter, shine",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "parkera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "park",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "kliva (-er, klev, klivit) ur",
        "back": "step out",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "dass (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "outhouse",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "toalett (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "toilet",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "hj\u00e4rta (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "heart",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "tv\u00e4tta (-r, -de, -t) sig",
        "back": "wash oneself",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "skicka (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "send",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "nubbe (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "snaps, flavored vodka",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "vodka (-n)",
        "back": "vodka",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "helan",
        "back": "the whole",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "halvan",
        "back": "the half",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "Sk\u00e5l!",
        "back": "Cheers!",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "sn\u00f6re (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "string",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "snapsvisa (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "drinking song",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "snaps (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "schnapps",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "visa (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "song",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "melodi (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "melody",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "Spritmuseum",
        "back": "The Museum of Spirits",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00e4sterskap (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "championship",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "ont i ryggen",
        "back": "have a backache",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "medan",
        "back": "while",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "vaniljbulle (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "vanilla bun",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "kantarell (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "chanterelles",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "sur (-t, -a)",
        "back": "annoyed",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "bl\u00e5b\u00e4rspaj (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "blueberry pie",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "skjuta (-er, sk\u00f6t, skjutit)",
        "back": "shoot",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "vaniljs\u00e5s (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "custard",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "frysa (fryser, fr\u00f6s, frusit)",
        "back": "freeze, be cold",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "bastu (-n, -r, -rna)",
        "back": "sauna",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "naken (naket, nakna)",
        "back": "naked",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "hoppa (-r, -de, -t) ner",
        "back": "jump down",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "relativa bisatser",
        "back": "relative clause",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "referera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "refer",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "Toscana",
        "back": "Tuscany",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "bottenv\u00e5ning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "ground floor",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "trots",
        "back": "although",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "tidssubjunktion (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "temporal conjunction",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "kontrast (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "contrast",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "nyansskillnad (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "nuance",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "spekulation (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "speculation",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "vana (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "habit",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "avsikt (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "intention",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00e5l (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "goal",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "Berlin",
        "back": "Berlin",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "lektion (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "lesson",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "bilradio (-n)",
        "back": "car radio",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "replik (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "reply",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "Tack f\u00f6r ikv\u00e4ll!",
        "back": "Thank you for a nice evening!",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "V\u00e4lkomna till bords!",
        "back": "Welcome to the table!",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "Ta f\u00f6r er!",
        "back": "Help yourselves!",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "Det \u00e4r bra f\u00f6r mig.",
        "back": "I'm good.",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "recept (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "recipe",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "sk\u00e5la (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "toast",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "rooibos",
        "back": "rooibos",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "dra (-r, drog, dragit) sig hem\u00e5t",
        "back": "go home",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "utrop (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "exclamation",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "glas\u00f6gon (-en)",
        "back": "glasses",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "komplimang (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "compliment",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "keps (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "cap",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "blus (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "blouse",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "nagellack (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "nail polish",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "armband (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "bracelet",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "sk\u00e4rp (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "belt",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6rh\u00e4nge (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "earring",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "vett och etikett",
        "back": "common sense and etiquette",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "expert (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "expert",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "kolumn (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "column",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "komma (-er, kom, kommit) i tid",
        "back": "arrive on time",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "lagom",
        "back": "just enough, the perfect amount",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "yttersko (-n, -r, -rna)",
        "back": "outdoor shoe",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4rd (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "host",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "innesko (-n, -r, -rna)",
        "back": "indoor shoe",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "present (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "gift",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "chokladask (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "box of chocolates",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "ta i hand",
        "back": "shake hands",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4rdinna (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "hostess",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "liknande",
        "back": "similar",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6ga (-t, -on, -onen)",
        "back": "eye",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "Tack f\u00f6r maten!",
        "back": "Thank you for the meal!",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "klar (-t, -a)",
        "back": "ready, finished",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "r\u00e4cka (-er, -te, -t)",
        "back": "be enough",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "Tack f\u00f6r senast!",
        "back": "Thank you for a nice evening/dinner/party!",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "etikettsregel (-n, etikettsregler, etikettsreglerna)",
        "back": "rule of etiquette",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "dags f\u00f6r",
        "back": "time for",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "bli (-r, blev, blivit) \u00f6ver",
        "back": "be left over",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "50-\u00e5rsfest (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "50th birthday party",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "inflyttningsfest (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "housewarming party",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "kickoff (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "launch event",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "klassfest (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "class party",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "knytis (knytkalas)",
        "back": "potluck",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "barnkalas (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "children\u2019s party",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "br\u00f6llop (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "wedding",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e5rets",
        "back": "this year's",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "t\u00e4nda (-er, -de, -t)",
        "back": "light",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "grill (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "grill",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e4ntligen",
        "back": "finally",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "fotbollsfest (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "soccer party",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "mot",
        "back": "against",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "fotbollsplan (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "soccer/football field",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "picknick (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "picnic",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "gymnastiksal (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "gym hall",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "sp\u00f6kboll (-en)",
        "back": "dodgeball",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "vigsel (-n, vigslar, vigslarna)",
        "back": "wedding ceremony",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e4ga (-er, -de, -t) rum",
        "back": "take place",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "kl\u00e4dsel (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "dress code",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "halvv\u00e4gs",
        "back": "halfway",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "danssko (-n, -r, -rna)",
        "back": "dance shoe",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "fira (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "celebrate",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "valfri kl\u00e4dsel",
        "back": "no dress code",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "Obs!",
        "back": "Note!",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "peng (vard)",
        "back": "money",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4lg\u00f6renhet (-en)",
        "back": "charity",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "toppendag (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "great day",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00e4ra",
        "back": "dear",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "nyf\u00f6dd (nyf\u00f6tt, nyf\u00f6dda)",
        "back": "newborn",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "Hoppas det g\u00e5r bra.",
        "back": "Hope it is ok.",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "klockslag (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "time (specific time of day)",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "sammans\u00e4ttning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "compound formation",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "vardagligt tal",
        "back": "everyday speech",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "asterisk (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "asterisk",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "fotbollsturnering (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "soccer/football tournament",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "b\u00f6r",
        "back": "should, must",
        "chapter": "Chapter14"
    },
    {
        "front": "generalisera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "generalize",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "tyst (-a)",
        "back": "silent",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e5ngt ifr\u00e5n",
        "back": "far away",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "veckonummer (veckonumret, \u2013, veckonumren)",
        "back": "number of the week",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "egentid",
        "back": "personal time",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "Thailand",
        "back": "Thailand",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "sp\u00e5rvagn (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "tram",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "bubbla (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "bubble",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "klaga (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "complain",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "nicka (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "nod",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "ljus (-et)",
        "back": "light",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00f6rker (m\u00f6rkret)",
        "back": "darkness",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "sucka (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "sigh",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "deppig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "depressed",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "by (-n, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "village",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "n\u00f6jd (n\u00f6jt, n\u00f6jda)",
        "back": "satisfied",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "sten (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "stone, rock",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "hotellrum (-met, \u2013, -men)",
        "back": "hotel room",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "exakt (-a)",
        "back": "exact",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "personnummer (personnumret, \u2013, personnumren)",
        "back": "social security number, identification number",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "ok\u00e4nd (-t, -a)",
        "back": "unknown",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "badplats (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "beach, bathing spot",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "fatta (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "understand, grasp",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "sj\u00e4lvst\u00e4ndiga pronomen",
        "back": "independent pronouns",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "abstrakt",
        "back": "abstract",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "magsjuk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "stomach sick, nauseous",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "p\u00e5 grund av",
        "back": "because of",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "smeknamn (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "nickname",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "genomsnittlig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "average",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "andranamn (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "middle name",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "trendig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "trendy",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "period (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "period",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "generation (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "generation",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "kungafamilj (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "royal family",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "idrottare (-n, \u2013, idrottarna)",
        "back": "athlete",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "nuf\u00f6rtiden",
        "back": "nowadays",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "unik (-t, -a)",
        "back": "unique",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "enorm (-t, -a)",
        "back": "enormous",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "djur\u00e4gare (-n, \u2013, -na)",
        "back": "pet owner",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "d\u00f6pa (-er, -te, -t)",
        "back": "name (a child, for example)",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "sl\u00e4ktnamn (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "surname",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rsvinna (-er, f\u00f6rsvann, f\u00f6rsvunnit)",
        "back": "disappear",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4derstreck (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "cardinal directions",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "st\u00f6dord (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "key word",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e5terber\u00e4tta (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "retell",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rbjuden (-et, -na)",
        "back": "forbidden",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "enligt lagen",
        "back": "according to the law",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "obehaglig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "unpleasant",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "ol\u00e4mplig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "inappropriate",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "Skatteverket",
        "back": "the Swedish Tax Agency",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "runsten (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "runestone",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "vikingagud (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "Viking god",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "krigisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "warlike",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "betydelse (-n, -r, -rna)",
        "back": "meaning",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "spjut (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "spear",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "strid (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "battle",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "Bibel (-n)",
        "back": "Bible",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "reflexiva possessiva pronomen",
        "back": "reflexive possessive pronouns",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "objekt (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "object",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "papegoja (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "parrot",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "hamster (-n, hamstrar, hamstrarna)",
        "back": "hamster",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e4ppeltr\u00e4d (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "apple tree",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "nyckel (nyckeln, nycklar, nycklarna)",
        "back": "key",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "dubbelbokad (-t, -de)",
        "back": "double booked",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "F\u00f6rs\u00e4kringskassan",
        "back": "Swedish Social Insurance Agency",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6r\u00e4ldrapenning (-en)",
        "back": "parental benefits",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "dubbel (-t, dubbla)",
        "back": "double",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "dubbla (-r, -de, -at)",
        "back": "double",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "lamm (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "lamb",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "damm (-et)",
        "back": "dust",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "mata (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "feed",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "matta (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "carpet",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "gran (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "fir tree",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "parkering (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "parking",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "kvinnlig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "female",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "dubbelnamn (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "double name, hyphenated name",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "manlig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "male",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "situation (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "situation",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "egentligen",
        "back": "actually",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "bero (-r, -dde, -t) p\u00e5",
        "back": "be due to",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "kalla (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "call",
        "chapter": "Chapter15"
    },
    {
        "front": "utbildning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "education",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "prov (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "test",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "lov (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "holiday, break",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e4mne (-t, -n, -na)",
        "back": "subject",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "str\u00e4ng (-t, -a)",
        "back": "strict",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "betyg (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "grade",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "stressa (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "stress",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "trumma (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "drum",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "band (-et, -en, -ena)",
        "back": "band",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "storasyster",
        "back": "older sister",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "etta (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "first grade",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "peppad (-t, -de)",
        "back": "excited, motivated",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "respekt (-en)",
        "back": "respect",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "motivera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "motivate",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "genom att",
        "back": "by, through",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "inte alls",
        "back": "not at all",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "utbildningssystem (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "education system",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "frivillig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "voluntary",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "obligatorisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "obligatory",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "termin (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "term, semester",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "grundskola (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "grade school",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "gymnasium (gymnasiet, gymnasier, gymnasierna)",
        "back": "high school",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "komvux",
        "back": "secondary education for adults",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rel\u00e4sning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "lecture",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "seminarium (seminariet, seminarier, seminarierna)",
        "back": "seminar",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rskoleklass (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "preschool class",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e5rskurs (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "year, grade",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "biologi (-n)",
        "back": "biology",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "bed\u00f6mning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "assessment",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "diskussion (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "discussion",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00e4rskild (-t, -a)",
        "back": "particular",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "inneh\u00e5lla (-er, -h\u00f6ll, -h\u00e5llit)",
        "back": "contain",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "fritidshem",
        "back": "after-school care",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "skoltid (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "schooling",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "kommunal (-t, -a)",
        "back": "municipal",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "friskola (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "independent school, charter school",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00f6sttermin (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "fall semester, autumn term",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e5rtermin (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "spring semester, spring term",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "jullov (-et)",
        "back": "Christmas holiday, Christmas break",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "sommarlov (-et)",
        "back": "summer vacation",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00f6stlov (-et)",
        "back": "autumn break",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "sportlov (-et)",
        "back": "February break",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "p\u00e5sklov (-et)",
        "back": "Easter break",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "p\u00e5sk (-en)",
        "back": "Easter",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "lagen s\u00e4ger",
        "back": "the law says",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "icke godk\u00e4nt",
        "back": "fail",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "gymnasieskola (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "upper secondary school",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00f6g (-t, -a)",
        "back": "high",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "komma (-er, kom, kommit) in",
        "back": "get admitted to",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "de flesta",
        "back": "most people",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "teoretisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "theoretical",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00f6gskolef\u00f6rberedande",
        "back": "university preparatory",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "naturvetenskapsprogram (-met, \u2013, -men)",
        "back": "science program",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "ekonomiprogram (-met, \u2013, -men)",
        "back": "business program",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "yrkesprogram (-met, \u2013, -men)",
        "back": "vocational program",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "fordons- och transportprogram (-met, \u2013, -men)",
        "back": "vehicle and transport program",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "barn- och fritidsprogram (-met, \u2013, -men)",
        "back": "child and leisure program",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "gymnasieprogram (-met, \u2013, -men)",
        "back": "upper secondary school program",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "bland annat",
        "back": "among other things",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "samh\u00e4llskunskap (-en)",
        "back": "social studies, civics",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "p\u00e5 s\u00e5 s\u00e4tt",
        "back": "in this way",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e4sa (-er, -te, -t) vidare",
        "back": "continue studying",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "vuxenutbildning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "adult education",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "folkh\u00f6gskola (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "folk high school",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "komplettera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "complete",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "tredjedel (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "a third",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "studenten (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "graduation",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "S\u00e5 h\u00e4r kan det g\u00e5 till.",
        "back": "Here's how it works.",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "utspring (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "graduation ceremony",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "skolg\u00e5rd (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "schoolyard",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "lastbil (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "truck",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "mottagning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "reception",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "universitetsstudier",
        "back": "university studies",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "jurist (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "lawyer, legal expert",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "niv\u00e5 (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "level",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "grundniv\u00e5",
        "back": "basic level",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "kandidatexamen",
        "back": "bachelor's degree",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "avancerad niv\u00e5",
        "back": "advanced level",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "masterexamen",
        "back": "master's degree",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "forskarniv\u00e5",
        "back": "research level",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "doktorsexamen",
        "back": "doctoral degree, PhD",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "yrkesh\u00f6gskola/YH-utbildning",
        "back": "higher vocational education",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "matcha (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "match",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "behov (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "need",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "arbetsmarknad (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "job market",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "teori (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "theory",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "praktik (-en)",
        "back": "internship",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "arbetsplats (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "workplace",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "kostnadsfri (-tt, -a)",
        "back": "free of charge",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "hyra (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "rent",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "finansiera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "finance",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "studiel\u00e5n (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "student loan",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "stat (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "state",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e5na (-r, -de, -t) ut",
        "back": "lend",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "skolg\u00e5ng (-en)",
        "back": "schooling",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "arbetsliv (-et)",
        "back": "working life",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "storebror (-brodern, -br\u00f6der, -br\u00f6derna)",
        "back": "older brother",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "fokusera (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "focus",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "extra\u00f6vning (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "extra exercises",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "idrott och h\u00e4lsa",
        "back": "physical education",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "pluggh\u00e4st (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "nerd, someone who studies hard",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "mattel\u00e4rare (-n)",
        "back": "mathematics teacher",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "historiel\u00e4rare (-n, \u2013, historiel\u00e4rarna)",
        "back": "history teacher",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "or\u00e4ttvis (-t, -a)",
        "back": "unfair",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "r\u00e4dd (-a)",
        "back": "afraid",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "kassa (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "cash register",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "garderob (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "wardrobe",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "halv\u00e5r (-et)",
        "back": "half a year",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "sugen (-et, -na)",
        "back": "eager",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "Chalmers tekniska h\u00f6gskola",
        "back": "Chalmers University of Technology",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "tuff (-t, -a)",
        "back": "tough",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00e4rdig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "finished",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "nanoteknik (-en)",
        "back": "nanotechnology",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00e5llbarhet (-en)",
        "back": "sustainability",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "taggad (-t, -de)",
        "back": "excited, pumped",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "lek (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "play",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "sitta (-er, satt, suttit) stilla",
        "back": "sit still",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "ton\u00e5ring (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "teenager",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "skoltr\u00f6tt (-a)",
        "back": "tired of school, lost motivation",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "spela (-r, -de, -t) gitarr",
        "back": "play guitar",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "skolka (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "skip school",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "g\u00e5 (-r, gick, g\u00e5tt) ut",
        "back": "go out",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "hoppa (-r, -de, -t) av",
        "back": "drop out",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "juristprogram (-met, \u2013, -men)",
        "back": "law program",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "advokatbyr\u00e5 (-n, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "law firm",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "motiverad (-t, -e)",
        "back": "motivated",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "andra chans",
        "back": "second chance",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "slacker/sl\u00f6fock (-en, -ar, -arna)",
        "back": "slacker",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "svenska som andraspr\u00e5k",
        "back": "Swedish as a second language",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "hem- och konsumentkunskap (hemkunskap) (-n)",
        "back": "home economics",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "moderna spr\u00e5k",
        "back": "modern languages",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "religionskunskap (-n)",
        "back": "religious studies",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "psykologi (-n)",
        "back": "psychology",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "teknik (-en)",
        "back": "technology",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "bild (-en)",
        "back": "art class",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "sl\u00f6jd (-en)",
        "back": "shop class, woodwork",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "omelett (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "omelet",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "utl\u00e4ndsk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "foreign",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "Litauen",
        "back": "Lithuania",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "Vilnius",
        "back": "Vilnius",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "byggnadsingenj\u00f6r (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "structural engineer",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "Warszawa",
        "back": "Warsaw",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "Japan",
        "back": "Japan",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00f6gskola (-n, -or, -orna)",
        "back": "university",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "frilansa (-r, -de, -t)",
        "back": "freelance",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6vers\u00e4ttare (-n, \u2013, \u00f6vers\u00e4ttarna)",
        "back": "translator",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "kvar",
        "back": "remaining",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "managementkonsult (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "management consultant",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "framtidsuttryck (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "future expressions",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "naturlig (-t, -a)",
        "back": "natural",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "process (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "process",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "logisk (-t, -a)",
        "back": "logical",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "konsekvens (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "consequence",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "neurokirurg (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "neurosurgeon",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "tidsadverb (-et, \u2013, -en)",
        "back": "adverbs of time",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "stadsbyggnad (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "urban planning",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "framtidsplan (-en, -er, -erna)",
        "back": "plan for the future",
        "chapter": "Chapter16"
    },
    {
        "front": "boende",
        "back": "housing, residence",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "tv\u00e5a",
        "back": "two-room apartment",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "trappa",
        "back": "stairs",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "balkong",
        "back": "balcony",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "kv\u00e4llssol",
        "back": "evening sun",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "morgonsol",
        "back": "morning sun",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "morgonkaffe",
        "back": "morning coffee",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "kollektiv",
        "back": "collective",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00f6bel",
        "back": "piece of furniture",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "husbil",
        "back": "motorhome",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "leva",
        "back": "live",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "dag f\u00f6r dag",
        "back": "day by day",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rort",
        "back": "suburb",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "bostadsr\u00e4tt",
        "back": "co-op apartment",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "hyresr\u00e4tt",
        "back": "rental apartment",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "tv\u00e4ttstuga",
        "back": "laundry room",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "kakelugn",
        "back": "tile stove",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6ppen spis",
        "back": "fireplace",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "tomt",
        "back": "garden, yard",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "pendla",
        "back": "commute",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "skick",
        "back": "condition",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "tv\u00e4ttmaskin",
        "back": "washing machine",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "elda",
        "back": "make a fire",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "hyresl\u00e4genhet",
        "back": "rental apartment",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rstahandskontrakt",
        "back": "primary lease",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "bostadsk\u00f6",
        "back": "housing queue",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "i andra hand",
        "back": "sublet",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "inneboende",
        "back": "lodger",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e5n",
        "back": "loan",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e4gare",
        "back": "owner",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00e5nadsavgift",
        "back": "monthly fee",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "typ",
        "back": "type",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "nyrenoverad",
        "back": "newly renovated",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "renoveringsobjekt",
        "back": "an object for renovation, a run-down place",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "uteplats",
        "back": "patio",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00f6gt i tak",
        "back": "high ceiling",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e5gt i tak",
        "back": "low ceiling",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "kokvr\u00e5",
        "back": "kitchenette",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "badrum",
        "back": "bathroom",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "viss",
        "back": "certain",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "wc",
        "back": "water closet, toilet",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rr\u00e5d",
        "back": "storage",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00e4llare",
        "back": "basement",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "vind",
        "back": "attic",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "flerfamiljshus",
        "back": "multi-family house",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "gemensam",
        "back": "communal",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "studentrum",
        "back": "student room, dorm room",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "radhus",
        "back": "semi-detached",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "parhus",
        "back": "semi-detached, two-family house",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "husb\u00e5t",
        "back": "houseboat",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "boyta",
        "back": "living space",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "ensamst\u00e5ende",
        "back": "single",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "sm\u00e5hus",
        "back": "small house",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "andrahandsl\u00e4genhet",
        "back": "sublet apartment",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "pendlingsavst\u00e5nd",
        "back": "commuting distance",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "leta",
        "back": "look for, search",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "plus",
        "back": "plus",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "uppv\u00e4rmning",
        "back": "heating",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "soph\u00e4mtning",
        "back": "garbage removal",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "sopor",
        "back": "garbage",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "solpanel",
        "back": "solar panel",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "kompost",
        "back": "compost",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "bostadsr\u00e4ttf\u00f6rening",
        "back": "condominium association",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rening",
        "back": "co-op",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "avgift",
        "back": "fee",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "r\u00e4nta",
        "back": "interest rate",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "amortering",
        "back": "amortization",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "regel",
        "back": "rule",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "stadgar",
        "back": "bylaws",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6lja",
        "back": "follow",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "t\u00e5gstation",
        "back": "train station",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "solsemester",
        "back": "sun holiday",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "skidsemester",
        "back": "skiing holiday",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "j\u00e4mf\u00f6relse",
        "back": "comparison",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "status",
        "back": "status",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "lika",
        "back": "equal",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "affisch",
        "back": "poster",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "elcykel",
        "back": "electric bicycle",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "moped",
        "back": "moped",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rdel",
        "back": "advantage, pro",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "nackdel",
        "back": "disadvantage, con",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rbereda",
        "back": "prepare",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "bostadsannons",
        "back": "housing ad, house listings",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "objekt",
        "back": "property",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "spa",
        "back": "spa",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "pizzaugn",
        "back": "pizza oven",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "charmig",
        "back": "charming",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "tv\u00e5plansvilla",
        "back": "two-story villa",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "jacuzzi",
        "back": "jacuzzi",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "tr\u00e4d\u00e4ck",
        "back": "wooden deck",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "murad",
        "back": "brick-built",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "g\u00e5ngavst\u00e5nd",
        "back": "walking distance",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "visning",
        "back": "viewing",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "boarea",
        "back": "living area",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "driftkostnad",
        "back": "operating cost",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00f6gstbjudande",
        "back": "highest bidder",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "planritning",
        "back": "floor plan",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4lplanerad",
        "back": "well planned",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "lyxig",
        "back": "luxurious",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "marmor",
        "back": "marble",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "exklusiv",
        "back": "exclusive",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "parkettgolv",
        "back": "parquet flooring",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "norrl\u00e4ge",
        "back": "northern exposure",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "sittgrupp",
        "back": "seating area",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "renoveringschans",
        "back": "opportunity for renovation",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "dr\u00f6mboende",
        "back": "dream home",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "runt h\u00f6rnet",
        "back": "around the corner",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6ppen planl\u00f6sning",
        "back": "open floor plan",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "middagsg\u00e4st",
        "back": "dinner guest",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "retro",
        "back": "retro",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "fungerande",
        "back": "functional",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "originalk\u00f6k",
        "back": "original kitchen",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "dr\u00f6mk\u00f6k",
        "back": "dream kitchen",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "plastmatta",
        "back": "vinyl flooring",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "tr\u00e4golv",
        "back": "wood floors",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "acceptpris",
        "back": "reserve price",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "matbord",
        "back": "dining table",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "sk\u00e5p",
        "back": "cupboard",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00e5t\u00f6lj",
        "back": "armchair",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "stol",
        "back": "chair",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "skrivbord",
        "back": "desk",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "soffbord",
        "back": "coffee table",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "taklampa",
        "back": "ceiling lamp",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "bokhylla",
        "back": "bookshelf",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "golvlampa",
        "back": "floorlamp",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "skrivbordslampa",
        "back": "desk lamp",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "krukv\u00e4xt",
        "back": "potted plant",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "utem\u00f6bel",
        "back": "outdoor furniture",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "badkar",
        "back": "bathtub",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "inredningsdetalj",
        "back": "interior detail",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "ta reda p\u00e5",
        "back": "find out",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "sovrum",
        "back": "bedroom",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "arbetsrum",
        "back": "office",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "hall",
        "back": "entrance hallway",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "veranda",
        "back": "veranda",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00e4klare",
        "back": "broker",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "sympatisk",
        "back": "sympathetic",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "besiktigat",
        "back": "inspected",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "dra om elen",
        "back": "rewire the electrical system",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "stajlad",
        "back": "styled",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "fr\u00e4sch",
        "back": "fresh",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00e4nga",
        "back": "hang",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "kristallkrona",
        "back": "crystal chandelier",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "gigantisk",
        "back": "gigantic",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "gr\u00e5beige",
        "back": "gray-beige",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00f6rnsoffa",
        "back": "corner sofa",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00f6rn",
        "back": "corner",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "designlampa",
        "back": "designer lamp",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "v\u00e4gg",
        "back": "wall",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "ordna efter f\u00e4rg",
        "back": "arrange by color",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "spis",
        "back": "stove",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "kylsk\u00e5p",
        "back": "fridge",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00f6kssk\u00e5p",
        "back": "fridge",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "kakel",
        "back": "tiles",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "pytteliten",
        "back": "tiny",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "gr\u00e4sklippare",
        "back": "lawnmower",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00e4rgburk",
        "back": "paint can",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "fuktig",
        "back": "damp",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "illa",
        "back": "bad",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "rabatt",
        "back": "flowerbed",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e4gga ett bud",
        "back": "make a bid",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "skriva",
        "back": "sign up",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "studsmatta",
        "back": "trampoline",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "sk\u00e4lla",
        "back": "bark",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "se ... ut",
        "back": "look ...",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "b\u00f6ja",
        "back": "conjugate",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "pigg",
        "back": "lively, alert",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "ovanf\u00f6r",
        "back": "above",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "till h\u00f6ger om",
        "back": "to the right of",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "till v\u00e4nster om",
        "back": "to the left of",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "kaffekopp",
        "back": "coffee cup",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "presentering",
        "back": "presentation",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "vertikal",
        "back": "vertical",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "horisontell",
        "back": "horizontal",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "fast",
        "back": "fixed",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "fixerad",
        "back": "fixed, attached",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00f6gtalare",
        "back": "speaker",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "komma \u00f6verens",
        "back": "agree",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e5nel\u00f6fte",
        "back": "mortgage pre-approval",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "leasa",
        "back": "lease",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "elbil",
        "back": "electric car",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "besiktningsman",
        "back": "inspector",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "budget",
        "back": "budget",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "laddstolpe",
        "back": "charging station",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "infartsparkering",
        "back": "driveway parking",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "sova p\u00e5 saken",
        "back": "sleep on it",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "kostnad",
        "back": "cost",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "besiktning",
        "back": "inspection",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "buda",
        "back": "bid",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00f6pare",
        "back": "buyer, customer",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "ordna",
        "back": "arrange",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "kontant",
        "back": "cash",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "spekulant",
        "back": "prospective buyer, speculator",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "budgivning",
        "back": "bidding",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "bindande",
        "back": "binding",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "dra tillbaka",
        "back": "withdraw",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00f6pekontrakt",
        "back": "purchase agreement",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e4ndra sig",
        "back": "change one's mind",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "ritning",
        "back": "floorplan",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "kategori",
        "back": "category",
        "chapter": "Chapter17"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00f6n",
        "back": "salary",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "omskola",
        "back": "retrain",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "deltid",
        "back": "part-time",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "flextid",
        "back": "flexible hours",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rm\u00e5n",
        "back": "benefit",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "fortbildning",
        "back": "continuing education",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "vabba",
        "back": "(vard) = ta ledigt f\u00f6r v\u00e5rd av sjukt barn, stay home from work to care for a sick child",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "anst\u00e4lld",
        "back": "employee",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "sjukskriven",
        "back": "on sick leave",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "vd",
        "back": "verkst\u00e4llande direkt\u00f6r, CEO",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rkortning",
        "back": "abbreviation",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "anst\u00e4llningstrygghet",
        "back": "job security",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "semesterdag",
        "back": "vacation day",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "friskv\u00e5rdstimme",
        "back": "wellness hour",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "pension",
        "back": "pension",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "heltid",
        "back": "full-time",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "chef",
        "back": "boss",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rlora",
        "back": "lose",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "arbetsgivare",
        "back": "employer",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "opinionsinstitut",
        "back": "opinion institute",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "balans",
        "back": "balance",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "flexibla arbetstider",
        "back": "flexible working hours",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "br\u00e5k",
        "back": "argument, fight",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "majoritet",
        "back": "majority",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "tanke",
        "back": "thought",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "karri\u00e4r",
        "back": "career",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "utvecklare",
        "back": "developer",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e4mna",
        "back": "leave",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00e4mta",
        "back": "pick up",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "trygg",
        "back": "secure, safe",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "statlig",
        "back": "governmental, state",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "myndighet",
        "back": "authority",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "strukturerad",
        "back": "structured",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "protokoll",
        "back": "protocol",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "oinspirerande",
        "back": "uninspiring",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "kundtj\u00e4nst",
        "back": "customer service",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "service",
        "back": "service",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "helt och h\u00e5llet",
        "back": "entirely, completely",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "arbetsnarkoman",
        "back": "workaholic",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "j\u00e4mt",
        "back": "consistently",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "mellanchef",
        "back": "middle manager",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "fikapaus",
        "back": "(= kaffepaus) coffee break",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "ta paus",
        "back": "take a break",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "sl\u00e5 upp",
        "back": "look up",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "kaffeapparat",
        "back": "coffee maker",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "kratta l\u00f6v",
        "back": "rake leaves",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "ta upp b\u00e5ten",
        "back": "bring in the boat",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "aprop\u00e5",
        "back": "speaking of",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "agent",
        "back": "agent",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "fel",
        "back": "wrong",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "hoppsan",
        "back": "oops",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "trevlig",
        "back": "nice, friendly",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00e5lla ig\u00e5ng",
        "back": "keep going",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "samtal",
        "back": "conversation",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rresten",
        "back": "incidentally",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "avsluta",
        "back": "finish, end",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "pryl",
        "back": "gadget, thing",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "apparat",
        "back": "device",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "kopieringsmaskin",
        "back": "copier, copy machine",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "kortl\u00e4sare",
        "back": "card reader",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "projektor",
        "back": "projector",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "kaffebryggare",
        "back": "coffee maker",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "diskmaskin",
        "back": "dishwasher",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "kanna",
        "back": "pot",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00e4lla",
        "back": "pour",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "markering",
        "back": "mark",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "skopa",
        "back": "scoop",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "trycka",
        "back": "press",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "knapp",
        "back": "button",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "timer",
        "back": "timer",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "sl\u00e5 p\u00e5",
        "back": "turn on",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "matchande",
        "back": "matching",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "port",
        "back": "port",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "pc",
        "back": "PC",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "adapter",
        "back": "adapter",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "vaktm\u00e4stare",
        "back": "caretaker",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "fj\u00e4rrkontroll",
        "back": "remote control",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "personlig",
        "back": "personal",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "kod",
        "back": "code",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "dubbelsidig",
        "back": "double sided",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "reception",
        "back": "reception",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "fylla p\u00e5",
        "back": "refill",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "korridor",
        "back": "corridor, hallway",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "it-avdelning",
        "back": "IT department",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "vara sist",
        "back": "be last",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "larm",
        "back": "alarm",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "hemlig",
        "back": "secret",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "telefonsamtal",
        "back": "phone conversation",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6vrig",
        "back": "other",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00f6",
        "back": "queue, line",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "bussbolag",
        "back": "bus company",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e4ngesedan",
        "back": "a long time ago",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "betalkort",
        "back": "credit card, debit card",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "sp\u00e4rra",
        "back": "block",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "st\u00f6ra",
        "back": "disturb",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "ing\u00e5",
        "back": "be included",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "fikarum",
        "back": "break room",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "Jag \u00e4r ledsen.",
        "back": "I\u2019m sorry.",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "ha fullt upp",
        "back": "be kept busy",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "ge upp",
        "back": "give up",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "senaste",
        "back": "latest",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "spellista",
        "back": "playlist",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00f6rlurar",
        "back": "earphones",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "personalavdelning",
        "back": "human resources department",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "support",
        "back": "support",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "var god dr\u00f6j",
        "back": "please hold",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "sitta i telefon",
        "back": "be on the phone",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e5terkomma",
        "back": "get back, return",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "ekonomiavdelning",
        "back": "finance department",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "formell",
        "back": "formal",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "mall",
        "back": "template",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "kontaktuppgift",
        "back": "contact information",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "tandklinik",
        "back": "dental clinic",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "leverans",
        "back": "delivery",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "reduktion",
        "back": "reduction",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "assimilation",
        "back": "assimilation",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6r\u00e4ndring",
        "back": "change",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "binda",
        "back": "bind",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6dla",
        "back": "lizard",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "insekt",
        "back": "insect",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "gr\u00e4dde",
        "back": "cream",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "badkl\u00e4der",
        "back": "swimwear",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "tydlig",
        "back": "clear",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e4mnesrad",
        "back": "subject line",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00e4lsningsfras",
        "back": "greeting",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "modell",
        "back": "model",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "anm\u00e4la",
        "back": "report, register",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "vabb",
        "back": "stay home from work to care for a sick child",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "sjukdom",
        "back": "illness",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "offert",
        "back": "quote",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "ledighet",
        "back": "time off",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "ledighetsans\u00f6kan",
        "back": "leave application",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "vikarie",
        "back": "substitute",
        "chapter": "Chapter18"
    },
    {
        "front": "kropp (-en, -ar, -arna) body",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "arm (-en, -ar, -arna) arm",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00e4l (-en, -ar, -arna) heel hals (-en, -ar, -arna) throat kn\u00e4 (-t, -n, -na) knee",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "vad (-en, -er, -erna) calf",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "fot (-en, f\u00f6tter, f\u00f6tterna) foot",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e5r (-et, \u2013, -en) thigh",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "hand (-en, h\u00e4nder, h\u00e4nderna) hand navel (-n, -navlar, navlarna) bellybutton nacke (-n, -ar, -arna) neck",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "midja (-n, -or, -orna) waist",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "rygg (-en, -ar, -arna) back",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00f6ft (-en, -er, -erna) hip",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "mage (-n, -ar, -arna) belly",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "br\u00f6st (-et, \u2013, -en) breast",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "axel (-n, axlar, axlarna) shoulder",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "finger (fingret, fingrar, fingrarna) finger",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "huvud (-et, -en, -ena) head",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "armb\u00e5ge (-n, -ar, -arna) elbow stj\u00e4rt (-en, -ar, -arna) buttocks rumpa (-n, -or, -orna) bum mun (-nen, -nar, -narna) mouth \u00f6ga (-t, -on, -onen) eye",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "ben (-et, \u2013, -en) leg",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "sidan 233",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "peka (-r, -de, -t) point",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "sidan 234",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "doktor (-n, -er, -erna) doctor, physician",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "ont i huvudet headache huvudv\u00e4rk (-en) headache var tredje every third",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "huvudv\u00e4rkstablett (-en, -er, -erna) headache pill, painkiller",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "tablett (-en, -er, -erna) pill",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "om dagen a day",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "snusa (-r, -de, -t) use snus, use snuff",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "motionera (-r, -de, -t) exercise",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "larmcentral (-en, -er, -erna) emergency call center",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "superkoncentrerad (-e) super concentrated",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "koncentrerad (-e) concentrated",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "e-sport (-en, -er, -erna) e-sports",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "turnering (-en, -ar, -arna) tournament dygna (-r, -de, -t) stay awake all night r\u00f6ra (r\u00f6r, r\u00f6rde, r\u00f6rt) p\u00e5 sig move",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "stel (-t, -a) stiff",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00f6mnig (-t, -a) sleepy",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "ordentlig (-t, -a) proper, orderly",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00f6mnvanor sleep habits",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "sidan 235",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "frekvens (-en, -er, -erna) frequency",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "arg angry",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "blinka (-r, -de, -t) blink",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "kortsvar short answer",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "sidan 236",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "dansa (-r, -de, -t) salsa dance salsa",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00e4ndis (-en, -ar, -arna) celebrity",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "kunglighet (-en, -er, -erna) royalty",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "seriefigur (-en, -er, -erna) cartoon character superhj\u00e4lte (-n, -ar, -arna) superhero komposit\u00f6r (-en, -er, -erna) composer",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "sidan 237",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "haka (-n, -or, -orna) chin",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6gonbryn (-et, \u2013, -en) eyebrow",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6ra (-t, \u00f6ron, \u00f6ronen) ear",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "tand (-en, t\u00e4nder, t\u00e4nderna) tooth",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00e5r (-et, \u2013, -en) hair",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "n\u00e4sborre (-n, -ar, -arna) nostril \u00f6gonfrans (-en, -ar, -arna) eyelash n\u00e4sa (-n, -or, orna) nose",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "kind (-en, -er, -erna) cheek panna (-n, -or, -orna) forehead \u00f6gonlock (-et, \u2013, -en) eyelid",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "rita (-r, -de, -t) draw",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "kroppsdel (-en, -ar, -arna) body part",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "sidan 238",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "m\u00e5 (-r, -dde, -tt) illa feel ill, feel nauseated",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "hosta (-r, -de, -t) cough",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "yr (-t, -a) dizzy",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "n\u00e4sblod nosebleed",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "influensa (-n, -or, -orna) flu",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "sv\u00e5rt att andas hard to breathe",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "svettas (svettas, svettades, svettats) to sweat snuvig (-t, -a) having a runny nose, sniffly stackare (-n, \u2013, stackarna) poor you",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "slem (-met) slime",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "snyta (-er, sn\u00f6t, snutit) blow one's nose",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "smitta (-r, -de, -t) infect, contagion",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "kr\u00e4kas (kr\u00e4ks, kr\u00e4ktes, kr\u00e4kts) throw up",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "feber (-n) fever",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "knipa (-er, knep, knipit) cramp",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "astmamedicin (-en, -er, -erna) asthma medicine",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "hj\u00e4rntum\u00f6r (-en, -er, -erna) brain tumor",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "migr\u00e4n (-en) migraine",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rkylning (-en, -ar, -arna) cold",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "hostmedicin (-en, -er, -erna) cough syrup",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "febertermometer (-n, febertermometrar, febertermometrarna) thermometer",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "irriterad (-t, -de) annoyed, irritated",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "tycka (-er, -te, -t) synd om",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "symtom (-et, \u2013, -en) symptom",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "sidan 239",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "sjunga (-er, sj\u00f6ng, sjungit) falskt sing off-key",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "mardr\u00f6m (-men, -mar, -marna) nightmare g\u00f6ra (g\u00f6r, gjorde, gjort) slut break up desperat (-a) desperate",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "operahatare (-n, \u2013, -na) opera hater",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "t\u00e4nka (-er, -te, t\u00e4nkt) positivt think positive",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rs\u00f6ka (-er, -te, -t) try respektfull (-t, -a) respectful \u00f6ronproppar earplugs",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "operafri (-tt, -a) opera-free",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "relationsexpert (-en, -er, -erna) relationship expert",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "identitet (-en, -er, -erna) identity",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "sidan 240",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "l\u00e5ngsam (-t, -ma) slow tonand (-t, -e) voiced tonl\u00f6s (-t, -a) voiceless",
        "back": "nan",
        "chapter": "Chapter19"
    },
    {
        "front": "notis",
        "back": "news item",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "rubrik",
        "back": "headline",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "underrubrik",
        "back": "subheading",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "stiga",
        "back": "rise",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "blixthalka",
        "back": "black ice",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "guldvinst",
        "back": "gold win, gold medal",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "arbetsl\u00f6shet",
        "back": "unemployment",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "g\u00e5 ner",
        "back": "go down",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00f6verraskning",
        "back": "surprise",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "urtidsdjur",
        "back": "prehistoric animal",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "ov\u00e4ntad",
        "back": "unexpected",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "fynd",
        "back": "discovery, find",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "vind",
        "back": "wind",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "hockeym\u00e4stare",
        "back": "hockey champion",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "sk\u00e5nsk",
        "back": "from Sk\u00e5ne (southern Sweden), Scanian",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "monster",
        "back": "monster",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "bostadsl\u00e5n",
        "back": "mortgage",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "kaos",
        "back": "chaos",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "trafik",
        "back": "traffic",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "arbetsf\u00f6rmedling",
        "back": "employment agency",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "riksbank",
        "back": "the national bank",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "meddela",
        "back": "announce",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00f6ja",
        "back": "raise",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "styrr\u00e4nta",
        "back": "key interest rate",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "procentenhet",
        "back": "percentage point",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "chefsekonom",
        "back": "chief economist",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rv\u00e5nad",
        "back": "surprised",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00f6jning",
        "back": "raise",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "rekordl\u00e5g",
        "back": "record low",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "binda",
        "back": "bind",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "marginal",
        "back": "margin, leeway",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "succ\u00e9",
        "back": "success",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "scen",
        "back": "stage, scene",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "g\u00f6ra comeback",
        "back": "come back, make a comeback",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "appl\u00e5d",
        "back": "applause",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "regi",
        "back": "direction",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "scenografi",
        "back": "set design, scenography",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rest\u00e4llning",
        "back": "performance, show",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "uppt\u00e4cka",
        "back": "discover",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "fossil",
        "back": "fossil",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "dinosaurie",
        "back": "dinosaur",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "huggtand",
        "back": "fang",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "rovdjur",
        "back": "predator",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "art",
        "back": "species",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "vara sl\u00e4kt med",
        "back": "be related to",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "uppt\u00e4ckt",
        "back": "discovery",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "arkeolog",
        "back": "archaeologist",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "st\u00e4lla ut",
        "back": "exhibit",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "motorv\u00e4g",
        "back": "highway",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "ishalka",
        "back": "icy road conditions",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "vinterd\u00e4ck",
        "back": "winter tires",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "k\u00f6ra i diket",
        "back": "drive into a ditch",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "krocka",
        "back": "crash",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "allvarlig",
        "back": "serious",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "skadad",
        "back": "wounded",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rsening",
        "back": "delay",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "busstrafik",
        "back": "bus traffic",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "flyta",
        "back": "float",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "kuvert",
        "back": "envelope",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "skraplott",
        "back": "scratch-off ticket",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "skrap",
        "back": "a scratch",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "storvinst",
        "back": "big win",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "nationalpark",
        "back": "national park",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rstasida",
        "back": "front page",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "riva",
        "back": "tear, demolish",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "onyttig",
        "back": "unhealthy",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00e4mre",
        "back": "worse",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "kakljud",
        "back": "cookie sound",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "bankanst\u00e4lld",
        "back": "bank employee",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "stj\u00e4la",
        "back": "steal",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "ekonominyheter",
        "back": "financial news",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "b\u00f6rs",
        "back": "stock exchange",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "euro",
        "back": "euro",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "dollar",
        "back": "dollar",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "st\u00e5 i",
        "back": "is worth",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "inflation",
        "back": "inflation",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "Norrland",
        "back": "Norrland, northern region of Sweden",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "Svealand",
        "back": "Svealand, central region of Sweden",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "G\u00f6taland",
        "back": "G\u00f6taland, southern region of Sweden",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "s\u00e4ndning",
        "back": "broadcast",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "skandal",
        "back": "scandal",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "vetenskapsnyhet",
        "back": "science news",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "demonstrera",
        "back": "demonstrate",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "kulturhistoriker",
        "back": "cultural historian",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "roa sig",
        "back": "amuse oneself",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "namninsamling",
        "back": "petition",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "r\u00e4dda",
        "back": "save, rescue",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "demonstrant",
        "back": "demonstrator, protester",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "kamp",
        "back": "struggle, fight",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "unders\u00f6ka",
        "back": "investigate, examine",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "bita",
        "back": "bite",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "sm\u00e5kaka",
        "back": "cookie",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "testperson",
        "back": "test subject, participant",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "bed\u00f6ma",
        "back": "assess",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "on\u00f6dig",
        "back": "unnecessary",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "bageriindustri",
        "back": "bakery industry",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "otrevlig",
        "back": "unpleasant",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "trettiosju\u00e5rig",
        "back": "thirty-seven-year-old",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "packa upp",
        "back": "unpack",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "bland",
        "back": "among",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "giftspindel",
        "back": "poisonous spider",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "spindel",
        "back": "spider",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "glasburk",
        "back": "glass jar",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "spindelexpert",
        "back": "spider expert",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "krypa in",
        "back": "crawl in",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "terrarium",
        "back": "terrarium",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "spela in",
        "back": "record",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "omv\u00e4xlande v\u00e4der",
        "back": "changeable weather",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "varierad",
        "back": "varied",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "\u00e5rstid",
        "back": "season",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "h\u00f6st",
        "back": "autumn, fall",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "vinter",
        "back": "winter",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "ostadig",
        "back": "unsteady",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "aprilv\u00e4der",
        "back": "April weather, unsteady weather",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "moln",
        "back": "cloud",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "dygnsmedeltemperatur",
        "back": "daily average temperature",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "grader Celsius",
        "back": "degrees Celsius, degrees centigrade",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "rekord",
        "back": "record",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "regnig",
        "back": "rainy",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "bl\u00e5sig",
        "back": "windy",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "fast",
        "back": "but",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "minusgrad",
        "back": "negative degree",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "sn\u00f6ig",
        "back": "snowy",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "mild",
        "back": "mild",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "Sibirien",
        "back": "Siberia",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "Golfstr\u00f6mmen",
        "back": "the Gulf Stream",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "Mexiko",
        "back": "Mexico",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "Skandinavien",
        "back": "Scandinavia",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "f\u00f6rv\u00e5nande",
        "back": "surprising",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "ankomst",
        "back": "arrival",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "definition",
        "back": "definition",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "solens upp- och nedg\u00e5ng",
        "back": "sunrise and sunset",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "sommarsolst\u00e5nd",
        "back": "summer solstice",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "vintersolst\u00e5nd",
        "back": "winter solstice",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "ull",
        "back": "wool",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "lager",
        "back": "layer",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "ta av",
        "back": "take off",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "tjock",
        "back": "thick",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    },
    {
        "front": "dryck",
        "back": "drink",
        "chapter": "Chapter20"
    }
]